<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37787373</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1399-3062</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Transplant infectious disease : an official journal of the Transplantation Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Transpl Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Infections after chimeric antigen receptor (CAR)-T-cell therapy for hematologic malignancies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e14157</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e14157</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/tid.14157</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chimeric antigen receptor (CAR)-T-cell therapies have revolutionized the management of acute lymphoblastic leukemia, non-Hodgkin lymphoma, and multiple myeloma but come at the price of unique toxicities, including cytokine release syndrome, immune effector cell-associated neurotoxicity syndrome, and long-term "on-target off-tumor" effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">All of these factors increase infection risk in an already highly immunocompromised patient population. Indeed, infectious complications represent the key determinant of non-relapse mortality after CAR-T cells. The temporal distribution of these risk factors shapes different infection patterns early versus late post-CAR-T-cell infusion. Furthermore, due to the expression of their targets on B lineage cells at different stages of differentiation, CD19, and B-cell maturation antigen (BCMA) CAR-T cells induce distinct immune deficits that could require different prevention strategies. Infection incidence is the highest during the first month post-infusion and subsequently decreases thereafter. However, infections remain relatively common even a year after infusion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Bacterial infections predominate early after CD19, while a more equal distribution between bacterial and viral causes is seen after BCMA CAR-T-cell therapy, and fungal infections are universally rare. Cytomegalovirus (CMV) and other herpesviruses are increasingly breported, but whether routine monitoring is warranted for all, or a subgroup of patients, remains to be determined. Clinical practices vary substantially between centers, and many areas of uncertainty remain, including CMV monitoring, antibacterial and antifungal prophylaxis and duration, use of immunoglobulin replacement therapy, and timing of vaccination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Risk stratification tools are available and may help distinguish between infectious and non-infectious causes of fever post-infusion and predict severe infections. These tools need prospective validation, and their integration in clinical practice needs to be systematically studied.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Transplant Infectious Disease published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kampouri</LastName><ForeName>Eleftheria</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8019-3073</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine and Infectious Disease Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Service, Lausanne University Hospital and University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Little</LastName><ForeName>Jessica S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rejeski</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine III-Hematology/Oncology, LMU University Hospital, LMU Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Cancer Consortium (DKTK), Munich site, and German Cancer Research Center, Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manuel</LastName><ForeName>Oriol</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7607-0943</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Service, Lausanne University Hospital and University of Lausanne, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammond</LastName><ForeName>Sarah P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Dana-Farber Cancer Institute, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Divisions of Hematology/Oncology and Infectious Diseases, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hill</LastName><ForeName>Joshua A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vaccine and Infectious Disease Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Division, Fred Hutchinson Cancer Center, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Transpl Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1398-2273</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BCMA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CAR-T-cell therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CD19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">infections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prediction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk stratification</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37787373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tid.14157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health (NIH), National Cancer Institute. CAR T Cells: Engineering Patients&#x2019; Immune Cells to Treat Their Cancers. Accessed May 18, 2023. https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/treatment/research/car-t-cells</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maude SL, Laetsch TW, Buechner J, et&#xa0;al. Tisagenlecleucel in children and young adults with B-cell lymphoblastic leukemia. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(5):439-448. doi:10.1056/nejmoa1709866</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maude SL, Frey N, Shaw PA, et&#xa0;al. Chimeric antigen receptor T cells for sustained remissions in leukemia. N Engl J Med. 2014;371(16):1507-1517. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1407222</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster SJ, Bishop MR, Tam CS, et&#xa0;al. Tisagenlecleucel in adult relapsed or refractory diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2019;380(1):45-56. doi:10.1056/nejmoa1804980</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster SJ, Svoboda J, Chong EA, et&#xa0;al. Chimeric antigen receptor T cells in refractory B-cell lymphomas. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(26):2545-2554. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1708566</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neelapu SS, Locke FL, Bartlett NL, et&#xa0;al. Axicabtagene ciloleucel CAR T-cell therapy in refractory large B-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(26):2531-2544. doi:10.1056/nejmoa1707447</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locke FL, Ghobadi A, Jacobson CA, et&#xa0;al. Long-term safety and activity of axicabtagene ciloleucel in refractory large B-cell lymphoma (ZUMA-1): a single-arm, multicentre, phase 1-2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2019;20(1):31-42. doi:10.1016/S1470-2045(18)30864-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Munoz J, Goy A, et&#xa0;al. KTE-X19 CAR T-cell therapy in relapsed or refractory mantle-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(14):1331-1342. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1914347</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah BD, Bishop MR, Oluwole OO, et&#xa0;al. KTE-X19 anti-CD19 CAR T-cell therapy in adult relapsed/refractory acute lymphoblastic leukemia: ZUMA-3 phase 1 results. Blood. 2021;138(1):11-22. doi:10.1182/blood.2020009098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramson JS, Palomba ML, Gordon LI, et&#xa0;al. Lisocabtagene maraleucel for patients with relapsed or refractory large B-cell lymphomas (TRANSCEND NHL 001): A multicentre seamless design study. Lancet. 2020;396(10254):839-852. doi:10.1016/s0140-6736(20)31366-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamdar M, Solomon SR, Arnason J, et&#xa0;al. Lisocabtagene maraleucel versus standard of care with salvage chemotherapy followed by autologous stem cell transplantation as second-line treatment in patients with relapsed or refractory large B-cell lymphoma (TRANSFORM): results from an interim analysis. Lancet. 2022;399(10343):2294-2308. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(22)00662-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locke FL, Miklos DB, Jacobson CA, et&#xa0;al. Axicabtagene ciloleucel as second-line therapy for large B-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2021;386(7):640-654. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2116133</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop MR, Dickinson M, Purtill D, et&#xa0;al. Second-line tisagenlecleucel or standard care in aggressive B-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2021;386(7):629-639. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2116596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neelapu SS, Dickinson M, Munoz J, et&#xa0;al. Axicabtagene ciloleucel as first-line therapy in high-risk large B-cell lymphoma: the phase 2 ZUMA-12 trial. Nat Med. 2022;28(4):735-742. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01731-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munshi NC, Anderson Jr. LD, Shah N, et&#xa0;al. Idecabtagene vicleucel in relapsed and refractory multiple myeloma. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(8):705-716. doi:10.1056/nejmoa2024850</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Otero P, Ailawadhi S, Arnulf B, et&#xa0;al. Ide-cel or standard regimens in relapsed and refractory multiple myeloma. N Engl J Med. 2023;388(11):1002-1014. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2213614</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berdeja JG, Madduri D, Usmani SZ, et&#xa0;al. Ciltacabtagene autoleucel, a B-cell maturation antigen-directed chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy in patients with relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma (CARTITUDE-1): a phase 1b/2 open-label study. Lancet. 2021;398(10297):314-324. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00933-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang V, Gauthier M, Decot V, Reppel L, Bensoussan D. Systematic review on CAR-T cell clinical trials up to 2022: academic center input. Cancers (Basel). 2023;15(4):1003. doi:10.3390/cancers15041003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale C, Strati P. CAR T-cell therapy for B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma and chronic lymphocytic leukemia: clinical trials and real-world experiences. Front Oncol. 2020;10:849. doi:10.3389/fonc.2020.00849</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto TN, Kishton RJ, Restifo NP. Developing neoantigen-targeted T cell-based treatments for solid tumors. Nat Med. 2019;25(10):1488-1499. doi:10.1038/s41591-019-0596-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldini CR, Ellis GI, Riley JL. CAR T cells for infection, autoimmunity and allotransplantation. Nat Rev Immunol. 2018;18(10):605-616. doi:10.1038/s41577-018-0042-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergmann C, M&#xfc;ller F, Distler JHW, et&#xa0;al. Treatment of a patient with severe systemic sclerosis (SSc) using CD19-targeted CAR T cells. Ann Rheum Dis. 2023;82(8):1117-1120. doi:10.1136/ard-2023-223952</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller F, Boeltz S, Knitza J, et&#xa0;al. CD19-targeted CAR T cells in refractory antisynthetase syndrome. Lancet. 2023;401(10379):815-818. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(23)00023-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackensen A, M&#xfc;ller F, Mougiakakos D, et&#xa0;al. Anti-CD19 CAR T cell therapy for refractory systemic lupus erythematosus. Nat Med. 2022;28(10):2124-2132. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-02017-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski K, Greco R, Onida F, et&#xa0;al. An international survey on grading, diagnosis, and management of Immune Effector Cell-Associated Hematotoxicity (ICAHT) following CAR T-cell therapy on behalf of the EBMT and EHA. Hemasphere. 2023;7(5):e889. https://journals.lww.com/hemasphere/Fulltext/2023/05000/An_International_Survey_on_Grading,_Diagnosis,_and.6.aspx</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DW, Santomasso BD, Locke FL, et&#xa0;al. ASTCT consensus grading for cytokine release syndrome and neurologic toxicity associated with immune effector cells. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2019;25(4):625-638. doi:10.1016/j.bbmt.2018.12.758</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brudno JN, Kochenderfer JN. Toxicities of chimeric antigen receptor T cells: recognition and management. Blood. 2016;127(26):3321-3330. doi:10.1182/blood-2016-04-703751</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brudno JN, Kochenderfer JN. Recent advances in CAR T-cell toxicity: mechanisms, manifestations and management. Blood Rev. 2019;34:45-55. doi:10.1016/j.blre.2018.11.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neelapu SS. Managing the toxicities of CAR T-cell therapy. Hematol Oncol. 2019;37(suppl 1):48-52. doi:10.1002/hon.2595</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schubert ML, Schmitt M, Wang L, et&#xa0;al. Side-effect management of chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T-cell therapy. Ann Oncol. 2021;32(1):34-48. doi:10.1016/j.annonc.2020.10.478</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hines MR, Knight TE, McNerney KO, et&#xa0;al. Immune effector cell-associated hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis-like syndrome. Transplant Cell Ther. 2023;29(7):438.e1-438.e16. doi:10.1016/j.jtct.2023.03.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kampouri E, Walti CS, Gauthier J, Hill JA. Managing hypogammaglobulinemia in patients treated with CAR-T-cell therapy: key points for clinicians. Expert Rev Hematol. 2022;15(4):305-320. doi:10.1080/17474086.2022.2063833</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds G, Sim B, Anderson MA, et&#xa0;al. Predicting infections in malignant haematology patients treated with CAR-T therapies: a systematic scoping review and narrative synthesis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2023. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2023.05.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for International Blood and Marrow Transplant Research (CIBMTR). 2021 Cellular Therapy Summary Slides. Accessed May 23, 2023. https://cibmtr.org/CIBMTR/Resources/Summary-Slides-Reports</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vora SB, Waghmare A, Englund JA, Qu P, Gardner RA, Hill JA. Infectious complications following CD19 chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy for children, adolescents, and young adults. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2020;7(5):1-9. doi:10.1093/OFID/OFAA121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkilineni L, Yates B, Steinberg SM, et&#xa0;al. Infectious complications of CAR T-cell therapy across novel antigen targets in the first 30 days. Blood Adv. 2021;5(23):5312-5322. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2021004896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F, Wei G, Liu Y, et&#xa0;al. Incidence and risk factors associated with infection after chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy for relapsed/refractory B-cell malignancies. Cell Transplant. 2021;30(79):1-9. doi:10.1177/09636897211025503</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill JA, Li D, Hay KA, et&#xa0;al. Infectious complications of CD19-targeted chimeric antigen receptor-modified T-cell immunotherapy. Blood. 2018;131(1):121-130. doi:10.1182/blood-2017-07-793760</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler NH, Dickinson M, Dreyling M, et&#xa0;al. Tisagenlecleucel in adult relapsed or refractory follicular lymphoma: the phase 2 ELARA trial. Nat Med. 2022;28(2):325-332. doi:10.1038/s41591-021-01622-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JM, Zucchetti E, Bachmeier CA, et&#xa0;al. Immune reconstitution and associated infections following axicabtagene ciloleucel in relapsed or refractory large B-cell lymphoma. Haematologica. 2020;106(4):haematol2019238634. doi:10.3324/haematol.2019.238634</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski K, Perez A, Iacoboni G, et&#xa0;al. The CAR-HEMATOTOX risk-stratifies patients for severe infections and disease progression after CD19 CAR-T in R/R LBCL. J Immunother Cancer. 2022;10(5):e004475. doi:10.1136/jitc-2021-004475</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried S, Avigdor A, Bielorai B, et&#xa0;al. Early and late hematologic toxicity following CD19 CAR-T cells. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2019;54(10):1643-1650. doi:10.1038/s41409-019-0487-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Hong R, Zhou L, et&#xa0;al. New-onset severe cytopenia after CAR-T cell therapy: analysis of 76 patients with relapsed or refractory acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Front Oncol. 2021;11:2433. doi:10.3389/fonc.2021.702644</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski K, Perez Perez A, Sesques P, et&#xa0;al. CAR-HEMATOTOX: a model for CAR T-cell related hematological toxicity in relapsed/refractory large B-cell lymphoma. Blood. 2021;138(24):2499-2513. doi:10.1182/blood.2020010543</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juluri KR, Wu V, Voutsinas JM, et&#xa0;al. Severe cytokine release syndrome is associated with hematologic toxicity following CD19 CAR T-cell therapy. Blood Adv. 2021;130(21):2295-2306. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2020004142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Romero FA, Taur Y, et&#xa0;al. Cytokine release syndrome grade as a predictive marker for infections in patients with relapsed or refractory B-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia treated with chimeric antigen receptor T cells. Clin Infect Dis. 2018;67(4):533-540. doi:10.1093/cid/ciy152</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haidar G, Dorritie K, Farah R, Bogdanovich T, Nguyen MH, Samanta P. Invasive mold infections after chimeric antigen receptor-modified T-cell therapy: a case series, review of the literature, and implications for prophylaxis. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(3):672-676. doi:10.1093/cid/ciz1127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordeiro A, Bezerra ED, Hirayama AV, et&#xa0;al. Late events after treatment with CD19-targeted chimeric antigen receptor modified T cells. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2020;26(1):26-33. doi:10.1016/j.bbmt.2019.08.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baird JH, Epstein DJ, Tamaresis JS, et&#xa0;al. Immune reconstitution and infectious complications following axicabtagene ciloleucel therapy for large B-cell lymphoma. Blood Adv. 2021;5(1):143-155. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2020002732</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittmann Dayagi T, Sherman G, Bielorai B, et&#xa0;al. Characteristics and risk factors of infections following CD28-based CD19 CAR-T cells. Leuk Lymphoma. 2021;62(7):1692-1701. doi:10.1080/10428194.2021.1881506</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little JS, Aleissa MM, Beluch K, et&#xa0;al. Low incidence of invasive fungal disease following CD19 chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy for non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Blood Adv. 2022;6(16):4821-4830. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2022007474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambhampati S, Sheng Y, Huang CY, et&#xa0;al. Infectious complications in relapsed refractory multiple myeloma patients after BCMA CAR T-cell therapy. Blood Adv. 2022;6(7):2045-2054. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2020004079</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan M, Nagavally S, Dhakal B, et&#xa0;al. Risk of infections with B-cell maturation antigen-directed immunotherapy in multiple myeloma. Blood Adv. 2022;6(8):2466-2470. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2021006178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josyula S, Pont MJ, Dasgupta S, et&#xa0;al. Pathogen-specific humoral immunity and infections in B cell maturation antigen-directed chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy recipients with multiple myeloma. Transplant Cell Ther. 2022;28(6):304.e1-304.e9. doi:10.1016/j.jtct.2022.03.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Li C, Xia J, et&#xa0;al. Humoral immune reconstitution after anti-BCMA CAR T-cell therapy in relapsed/refractory multiple myeloma. Blood Adv. 2021;5(23):5290-5299. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2021004603</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue JM, Peres LC, Hashmi H, et&#xa0;al. Early cytopenias and infections after standard of care idecabtagene vicleucel in relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma. Blood Adv. 2022;6(24):6109-6119. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2022008320</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyar-Katz O, Kikozashvili N, Bar On Y, et&#xa0;al. Characteristics and recognition of early infections in patients treated with commercial anti-CD19 CAR-T cells. Eur J Haematol. 2021;108:1-9. doi:10.1111/ejh.13712</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hay KA, Hanafi LA, Li D, et&#xa0;al. Kinetics and biomarkers of severe cytokine release syndrome after CD19 chimeric antigen receptor-modified T-cell therapy. Blood. 2017;130(21):2295-2306. doi:10.1182/blood-2017-06-793141</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wudhikarn K, Palomba ML, Pennisi M, et&#xa0;al. Infection during the first year in patients treated with CD19 CAR T cells for diffuse large B cell lymphoma. Blood Cancer J. 2020;10(8):79. doi:10.1038/s41408-020-00346-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frigault MJ, Nikiforow S, Mansour MK, et&#xa0;al. Tocilizumab not associated with increased infection risk after CAR T-cell therapy: implications for COVID-19? Blood. 2020;136(1):137-139. doi:10.1182/blood.2020006216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain T, Olson TS, Locke FL. How I treat cytopenias after CAR T-cell therapy. Blood. 2023;141(20):2460-2469. doi:10.1182/blood.2022017415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meir J, Abid MA, Abid MB. State of the CAR-T: risk of infections with chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy and determinants of SARS-CoV-2 vaccine responses. Transplant Cell Ther. 2021;27(12):973-987. doi:10.1016/j.jtct.2021.09.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Y, Zhang J, Li J, et&#xa0;al. Cytopenias following anti-CD19 chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T cell therapy: a systematic analysis for contributing factors. Ann Med. 2022;54(1):2951-2965. doi:10.1080/07853890.2022.2136748</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachy E, Le Gouill S, Di Blasi R, et&#xa0;al. A real-world comparison of tisagenlecleucel and axicabtagene ciloleucel CAR T cells in relapsed or refractory diffuse large B cell lymphoma. Nat Med. 2022;28(10):2145-2154. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01969-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusaroli M, Isgr&#xf2; V, Cutroneo PM, et&#xa0;al. Post-marketing surveillance of CAR-T-cell therapies: analysis of the FDA Adverse Event Reporting System (FAERS) database. Drug Saf. 2022;45(8):891-908. doi:10.1007/s40264-022-01194-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill JA, Giralt S, Torgerson TR, Lazarus HM. CAR-T-and a side order of IgG, to go?-Immunoglobulin replacement in patients receiving CAR-T cell therapy. Blood Rev. 2019;38. doi:10.1016/j.blre.2019.100596</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliley JL, Tipton CM, Liesveld J, et&#xa0;al. Long-lived plasma cells are contained within the CD19&#x2212;CD38hiCD138+ subset in human bone marrow. Immunity. 2015;43(1):132-145. doi:10.1016/J.IMMUNI.2015.06.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhoj VG, Arhontoulis D, Wertheim G, et&#xa0;al. Persistence of long-lived plasma cells and humoral immunity in individuals responding to CD19-directed CAR T-cell therapy. Blood. 2016;128(3):360-370. doi:10.1182/blood-2016-01-694356</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill JA, Krantz EM, Hay KA, et&#xa0;al. Durable preservation of antiviral antibodies after CD19-directed chimeric antigen receptor T-cell immunotherapy. Blood Adv. 2019;3(22):3590-3601. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2019000717</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walti CS, Krantz EM, Maalouf J, et&#xa0;al. Antibodies to vaccine-preventable infections after CAR-T-cell therapy for B-cell malignancies. JCI Insight. 2021;6(11):e146743. doi:10.1172/jci.insight.146743</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strati P, Varma A, Adkins S, et&#xa0;al. Hematopoietic recovery and immune reconstitution after axicabtagene ciloleucel in patients with large B-cell lymphoma. Haematologica. 2021;106(10):2667-2672. doi:10.3324/haematol.2020.254045</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DE, Maude SL, Callahan CA, DiNofia AM, Grupp SA, Heimall JR. Subcutaneous immunoglobulin replacement following CD19-specific chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy for B-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia in pediatric patients. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2020;67(3):1-4. doi:10.1002/pbc.28092</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey&#xe0;-Mart&#xed;nez A, Alonso-Saladrigues A, Garc&#xed;a AP, et&#xa0;al. Kinetics of humoral deficiency in CART19-treated children and young adults with acute lymphoblastic leukaemia. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2021;56(2):376-386. doi:10.1038/s41409-020-01027-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine JE, Grupp SA, Pulsipher MA, et&#xa0;al. Pooled safety analysis of tisagenlecleucel in children and young adults with B cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia. J Immunother Cancer. 2021;9(8):e002287. doi:10.1136/jitc-2020-002287</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambhampati S, Sheng Y, Huang CY, et&#xa0;al. Infectious complications in patients with relapsed refractory multiple myeloma after BCMA CAR T-cell therapy. Blood Adv. 2022;6(7):2045-2054. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2020004079</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski K, Perez Perez A, Iacoboni G, et&#xa0;al. Biphasic neutrophil recovery after CD19 CART in R/R LBCL is associated with superior PFS/OS, robust CAR T-cell expansion in relation to baseline tumor volume, and a decrease of systemic inflammation over time. Blood. 2022;140(suppl 1):4549-4551. doi:10.1182/blood-2022-167632</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Deng Q, Henderson J, et&#xa0;al. Targetable cellular etiology of prolonged cytopenia following CD19 CAR T-cell therapy. Blood. 2022;140(suppl 1):4502-4503. doi:10.1182/blood-2022-166308</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telli Dizman G, Aguado JM, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Ruiz M. Risk of infection in patients with hematological malignancies receiving CAR T-cell therapy: systematic review and meta-analysis. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2022;20(11):1455-1476. doi:10.1080/14787210.2022.2128762</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo H, Wang N, Huang L, et&#xa0;al. Inflammatory signatures for quick diagnosis of life-threatening infection during the CAR T-cell therapy. J Immunother Cancer. 2019;7(1):271. doi:10.1186/s40425-019-0767-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamilos G, Lionakis MS, Kontoyiannis DP. Call for action: invasive fungal infections associated with ibrutinib and other small molecule kinase inhibitors targeting immune signaling pathways. Clin Infect Dis. 2018;66(1):140-148. doi:10.1093/cid/cix687</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little JS, Shah P, Sperling AS, et&#xa0;al. Infectious complications in patients treated with idecabtagene vicleucel for relapsed and refractory multiple myeloma. Blood. 2021;138:3839. doi:10.1182/blood-2021-153942</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little J, Tandon M, Hong JS, et&#xa0;al. Respiratory infections predominate after day 100 following B-cell maturation antigen-directed CAR T-cell therapy. Blood Adv. 2023. doi:10.1182/BLOODADVANCES.2023010524</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski K, Hansen DK, Bansal R, et&#xa0;al. The CAR-Hematotox score as a prognostic model of toxicity and response in patients receiving BCMA-directed CAR-T for relapsed/refractory multiple myeloma. Blood. 2022;140(suppl 1):7506-7508. doi:10.1182/blood-2022-165266</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden PJ, Roddie C, Bader P, et&#xa0;al. Management of adults and children receiving CAR T-cell therapy: 2021 best practice recommendations of the European Society for Blood and Marrow Transplantation (EBMT) and the Joint Accreditation Committee of ISCT and EBMT (JACIE) and the European Haemato. Ann Oncol. 2022;33(3):259-275. doi:10.1016/j.annonc.2021.12.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Los-Arcos I, Iacoboni G, Aguilar-Guisado M, et&#xa0;al. Recommendations for screening, monitoring, prevention, and prophylaxis of infections in adult and pediatric patients receiving CAR T-cell therapy: a position paper. Infection. 2021;49(2):215-231. doi:10.1007/s15010-020-01521-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul F, Vicente C, Courbon C, et&#xa0;al. Prevention and management of infections in patients undergoing CAR T-cell therapy: recommendations of the Francophone Society of Bone Marrow Transplantation and Cellular Therapy (SFGM-TC). Bull Cancer. 2021;108(12S):S90-S97. doi:10.1016/j.bulcan.2021.11.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill JA, Seo SK. How I prevent infections in patients receiving CD19-targeted chimeric antigen receptor T cells for B-cell malignancies. Blood. 2020;136(8):925-935. doi:10.1182/blood.2019004000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudiol C, Lewis RE, Strati P, Kontoyiannis DP. Chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy for the treatment of lymphoid malignancies: is there an excess risk for infection? Lancet Haematol. 2021;8(3):e216-e228. doi:10.1016/S2352-3026(20)30376-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wudhikarn K, Perales MA. Infectious complications, immune reconstitution, and infection prophylaxis after CD19 chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2022;57(10):1477-1488. doi:10.1038/s41409-022-01756-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santomasso BD, Nastoupil LJ, Adkins S, et&#xa0;al. Management of immune-related adverse events in patients treated with chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy: ASCO guideline. J Clin Oncol. 2021;39(35):3978-3992. doi:10.1200/JCO.21.01992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kansagra AJ, Frey NV, Bar M, et&#xa0;al. Clinical utilization of chimeric antigen receptor T cells in B cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia: an expert opinion from the European Society for Blood and Marrow Transplantation and the American Society for Blood and Marrow Transplantation. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2019;25(3):e76-e85. doi:10.1016/j.bbmt.2018.12.068</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski K, Kunz WG, Rudelius M, et&#xa0;al. Severe Candida glabrata pancolitis and fatal Aspergillus fumigatus pulmonary infection in the setting of bone marrow aplasia after CD19-directed CAR T-cell therapy-a case report. BMC Infect Dis. 2021;21(1):121. doi:10.1186/s12879-020-05755-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds G, Hall VG, Teh BW. Vaccine schedule recommendations and updates for patients with hematologic malignancy post-hematopoietic cell transplant or CAR T-cell therapy. Transpl Infect Dis. 2023;e14109. doi:10.1111/TID.14109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walti CS, Loes AN, Shuey K, et&#xa0;al. Humoral immunogenicity of the seasonal influenza vaccine before and after CAR-T-cell therapy: a prospective observational study. J Immunother Cancer. 2021;9(10):e003428. doi:10.1136/JITC-2021-003428</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill JA, Martens MJ, Young JAH, et&#xa0;al. SARS-CoV-2 vaccination in the first year after allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplant: a prospective, multicentre, observational study. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;59:101983. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.101983</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen GL, Mithani R, Kapoor A, et&#xa0;al. Safety and immunogenicity of mRNA-1345, an mRNA-based RSV vaccine in younger and older adult cohorts: results from a phase 1, randomized clinical trial. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9(suppl 2):ofac492312. doi:10.1093/ofid/ofac492.312</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold DE, Maude SL, Callahan CA, et&#xa0;al. Review of indications for immunoglobulin (IG) use: narrowing the gap between supply and demand. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2019;67(3):S1-S46. doi:10.1016/j.blre.2017.09.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez EE, Orange JS, Bonilla F, et&#xa0;al. Update on the use of immunoglobulin in human disease: a review of evidence. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2017;139(3):S1-S46. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2016.09.023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raanani P, Gafter-Gvili A, Paul M, Ben-Bassat I, Leibovici L, Shpilberg O. Immunoglobulin prophylaxis in hematological malignancies and hematopoietic stem cell transplantation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2008;(4):CD006501. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD006501.pub2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhella S, Majhail NS, Betcher J, et&#xa0;al. Choosing wisely BMT: American Society for Blood and Marrow Transplantation and Canadian Blood and Marrow Transplant Group's list of 5 tests and treatments to question in blood and marrow transplantation. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2018;24(5):909-913. doi:10.1016/j.bbmt.2018.01.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahadeo KM, Khazal SJ, Abdel-Azim H, et&#xa0;al. Management guidelines for paediatric patients receiving chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2019;16(1):45-63. doi:10.1038/s41571-018-0075-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saylor C, Dadachova E, Casadevall A. Monoclonal antibody-based therapies for microbial diseases. Vaccine. 2009;27(suppl 6):G38-G46. doi:10.1016/j.vaccine.2009.09.105</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenks JD, Aslam S, Horton LE, et&#xa0;al. Early monoclonal antibody administration can reduce both hospitalizations and mortality in high-risk outpatients with coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19). Clin Infect Dis. 2022;74(4):752-753. doi:10.1093/cid/ciab522</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer T, Tzannou I, Wu M, et&#xa0;al. Posoleucel, an allogeneic, off-the-shelf multivirus-specific T-cell therapy, for the treatment of refractory viral infections in the post-HCT setting. Clin Cancer Res. 2023;29(2):324-330. doi:10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-22-2415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly RJ, Prockop S, Hasan AN, Koehne G, Doubrovina E. Virus-specific T-cell banks for &#x201c;off the shelf&#x201d; adoptive therapy of refractory infections. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2016;51(9):1163-1172. doi:10.1038/bmt.2016.17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciurea SO, Schafer JR, Bassett R, et&#xa0;al. Phase 1 clinical trial using mbIL21 ex vivo-expanded donor-derived NK cells after haploidentical transplantation. Blood. 2017;130(16):1857-1868. doi:10.1182/blood-2017-05-785659</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Market M, Angka L, Martel AB, et&#xa0;al. Flattening the COVID-19 curve with natural killer cell based immunotherapies. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1512. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2020.01512</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kampouri E, Hill JA, Dioverti V. COVID-19 after hematopoietic cell transplantation and chimeric antigen receptor (CAR)-T-cell therapy. Transpl Infect Dis. Published online September 28, 2023:e14144. doi: 10.1111/tid.14144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe1;rquez-Algaba E, Iacoboni G, Pernas B, et&#xa0;al. Impact of cytomegalovirus replication in patients with aggressive B cell lymphoma treated with chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy. Transplant Cell Ther. 2022;28(12):851.e1-851.e8. doi:10.1016/j.jtct.2022.09.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solano de la Asunci&#xf3;n C, Hernani R, Albert E, et&#xa0;al. Cytomegalovirus DNAemia in hematological patients undergoing CD19-directed CAR-T cell therapy: should it be systematically monitored? Clin Microbiol Infect. 2023;29(8):1093-1095. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2023.05.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Herr M, Nowak J, et&#xa0;al. Cytomegalovirus reactivation after CD19 CAR T-cell therapy is clinically significant. Haematologica. 2023;108(2):615-620. doi:10.3324/haematol.2022.281719</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Mao X, Que Y, et&#xa0;al. Viral infection/reactivation during long-term follow-up in multiple myeloma patients with anti-BCMA CAR therapy. Blood Cancer J. 2021;11(10):5-8. doi:10.1038/s41408-021-00563-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heldman MR, Ma J, Gauthier J, et&#xa0;al. CMV and HSV pneumonia after immunosuppressive agents for treatment of cytokine release syndrome due to chimeric antigen receptor-modified T (CAR-T)-cell immunotherapy. J Immunother. 2021;44(9):351-354. doi:10.1097/CJI.0000000000000388</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousin E, Belicard F, Michel L, et&#xa0;al. Severe cytomegalovirus disease with encephalitis after CAR-T cell therapy: a rare but potentially fatal complication. J Med Virol. 2021;93(11):6398-6403. doi:10.1002/jmv.27257</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korell F, Schubert ML, Sauer T, et&#xa0;al. Infection complications after lymphodepletion and dosing of chimeric antigen receptor T (CAR-T) cell therapy in patients with relapsed/refractory acute lymphoblastic leukemia or B cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancers (Basel). 2021;13(7):1684. doi:10.3390/cancers13071684</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zu C, Xu Y, Wang Y, et&#xa0;al. Cytomegalovirus retinitis and retinal detachment following chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy for relapsed/refractory multiple myeloma. Curr Oncol. 2022;29(2):490-496. doi:10.3390/curroncol29020044</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kampouri E, Ibrahimi S, Hecht J, et&#xa0;al. CMV and HHV-6 after chimeric antigen receptor (CAR)-T-cell immunotherapy for B-cell malignancies: a prospective study. Transplant Cell Ther. 2023;29:S210-S211. doi:10.1016/S2666-6367(23)00341-X</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavi N, Okasha D, Sabo E, Oren I, Benyamini N, Bar-Yoseph H. Severe cytomegalovirus enterocolitis developing following daratumumab exposure in three patients with multiple myeloma. Eur J Haematol. 2018. doi:10.1111/ejh.13164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabata R, Sato N, Yamauchi N, et&#xa0;al. Cytomegalovirus reactivation in patients with multiple myeloma administered daratumumab-combination regimens. Ann Hematol. 2022;101(2):465-467. doi:10.1007/s00277-021-04525-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handley G, Hasbun R, Okhuysen P. Human herpesvirus 6 and central nervous system disease in oncology patients: a retrospective case series and literature review. J Clin Virol. 2021;136:104740. doi:10.1016/j.jcv.2021.104740</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah M, Kuhnl A, Shields G, et&#xa0;al. Human herpesvirus 6 encephalitis following axicabtagene ciloleucel treatment for refractory diffuse large B cell lymphoma. Hemasphere. 2021;5(3):e535. doi:10.1097/HS9.0000000000000535</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebechi MT, Bork JT, Riedel DJ. HHV-6 encephalitis after chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy (CAR-T): 2 case reports and a brief review of the literature. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8(11):ofab470. doi:10.1093/ofid/ofab470</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spanjaart AM, van der Valk FM, van Rooijen G, Brouwer MC, Kersten MJ. Confused about confusion. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(1):80-87. doi:10.1056/NEJMcps2114818</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J, Zhu X, Mao X, Huang L, Meng F, Zhou J. Severe early hepatitis B reactivation in a patient receiving anti-CD19 and anti-CD22 CAR T cells for the treatment of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. J Immunother Cancer. 2019;7(1):315. doi:10.1186/s40425-019-0790-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao W, Wei J, Wang N, et&#xa0;al. Entecavir prophylaxis for hepatitis B virus reactivation in patients with CAR T-cell therapy. Blood. 2020;136(4):516-519. doi:10.1182/blood.2020004907</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strati P, Nastoupil LJ, Fayad LE, Samaniego F, Adkins S, Neelapu SS. Safety of CAR T-cell therapy in patients with B-cell lymphoma and chronic hepatitis B or C virus infection. Blood. 2019;133(26):2800-2802. doi:10.1182/blood.2019000888</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Liu Y, Tan X, et&#xa0;al. Safety and efficacy of chimeric antigen receptor (CAR)-T-cell therapy in persons with advanced B-cell cancers and hepatitis B virus-infection. Leukemia. 2020;34(10):2704-2707. doi:10.1038/s41375-020-0936-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy KR, Beavers KL, Hammond SP, Lim JK, Falck-Ytter YT. American Gastroenterological Association Institute guideline on the prevention and treatment of hepatitis B virus reactivation during immunosuppressive drug therapy. Gastroenterology. 2015;148(1):215-217. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2014.10.039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang JP, Somerfield MR, Alston-Johnson DE, et&#xa0;al. Hepatitis B virus screening for patients with cancer before therapy: American Society of Clinical Oncology Provisional Clinical Opinion Update. J Clin Oncol. 2015;33(19):2212-2220. doi:10.1200/JCO.2015.61.3745</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski K, Blumenberg V, Iacoboni G, et&#xa0;al. Identifying early infections in the setting of CRS with routine and exploratory serum proteomics and the HT10 score following CD19 CAR-T for relapsed/refractory B-NHL. Hemasphere. 2023;7(4):e858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell MZ, Mara KC, Bansal R, et&#xa0;al. Procalcitonin as a biomarker for predicting bacterial infection in chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy recipients. Cancer Med. 2023;12(8):9228-9235. doi:10.1002/cam4.5665</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diorio C, Shaw PA, Pequignot E, et&#xa0;al. Diagnostic biomarkers to differentiate sepsis from cytokine release syndrome in critically ill children. Blood Adv. 2020;4(20):5174-5183. doi:10.1182/bloodadvances.2020002592</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith M, Dai A, Ghilardi G, et&#xa0;al. Gut microbiome correlates of response and toxicity following anti-CD19 CAR T cell therapy. Nat Med. 2022;28(4):713-723. doi:10.1038/s41591-022-01702-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein-Thoeringer CK, Saini NY, Zamir E, et&#xa0;al. A non-antibiotic-disrupted gut microbiome is associated with clinical responses to CD19-CAR-T cell cancer immunotherapy. Nat Med. 2023;29(4):906-916. doi:10.1038/s41591-023-02234-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski K, Wang Y, Albanyan O, et&#xa0;al. The CAR-Hematotox score identifies patients at high risk for hematological toxicity, infections and poor clinical outcomes following brexucabtagene autoleucel in relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2022;140(suppl 1):651-653. doi:10.1182/blood-2022-167329</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood &amp; Marrow Transplant Clinical Trials Network (BMT CTN). Diagnosing and Grading Infectious Diseases. Investigator and Research Staff Resources. Accessed May 26, 2023. https://bmtctn.net/administrative-manual-procedures-moppolicy-guidelines</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>