<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37780980</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2772-3682</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Lancet regional health. Southeast Asia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Reg Health Southeast Asia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cancer awareness, diagnosis and treatment needs in Mizoram, India: evidence from 18 years trends (2003-2020).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100281</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100281</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100281</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lansea.2023.100281</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Despite being the second least populated state, Mizoram exhibits the highest incidence rate of cancer in India. Its inhabitants, constituting an endogamous and isolated population, have embraced their own distinct culture, way of life and dietary preferences, setting them apart from the rest of mainland India. In 2003, the Mizoram Population Based Cancer Registry (PBCR) was established under the auspices of the National Centre for Disease Informatics and Research (NCDIR), a division of the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR), in collaboration with the Department of Health &amp; Family Welfare of the Government of Mizoram, India.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cancer incidence and mortality data were extracted from the Mizoram PBCR spanning the years 2003-2020. The Age Standardized Incidence Rate (ASIR) and Age Standardized Mortality Rate (ASMR) were computed per 100,000 individuals, utilizing Segi's World Standard Population as the benchmark. The trajectory of these changes was analysed employing the Joinpoint Regression Analysis Program, Version 4.9.1.0.13, to unveil the Annual Percent Change (APC) with a 95% Confidence Interval and a Significance test (p&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.05) using Monte Carlo Permutation. The resulting graphical visualizations were generated using Flourish Studio.15.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The overall ASIR for all cancer sites among men was 197.2 per 100,000, while for women, it was 164.9 per 100,000. Among men, the most prevalent cancer site was the Stomach (ASIR&#xa0;=&#xa0;41.4), followed by Head &amp; Neck, Lung, Oesophagus, Colorectal, Liver, Urinary, Non-Hodgkin's Lymphoma and Prostate cancers. Conversely, among women, Lung cancer exhibited the highest incidence (ASIR&#xa0;=&#xa0;26.7), succeeded by Cervical, Breast, Stomach, Head &amp; Neck, Colorectal, Oesophagus, Liver and Ovarian cancers. Stomach cancer emerged as the leading cause of death among men (ASMR&#xa0;=&#xa0;22.6) and among women, Lung cancer held the highest ASMR (15.9). Joinpoint regression analysis revealed a rising trend in incidence and mortality over time for overall cancer sites. Among the primary cancer sites contributing to incidence and mortality, an increase in APC was observable for all, except Stomach cancer, in both men and women. The diagnostic approach, except for cases of cancer with unknown primary sites, involved a microscopic method.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This cross-sectional study examines PBCR reports spanning from 2003 to 2020, shedding light on a consistent uptick in cancer incidence and mortality trends in Mizoram. Stomach cancer emerges as the most prevalent and primary cause of cancer-related deaths among men, while Lung cancer takes a parallel role in women. The elevated cancer incidence and the growing trend among younger generations might stem from the static lifestyle and dietary patterns prevalent within the endogamous tribal population, potentially contributing to a genetic predisposition. The escalation in mortality rates could be attributed to a dearth of specialized diagnostic facilities and skilled human resources, treatment strategies guided by genomic research and transportation challenges. This underscores the urgent requirement for comprehensive scientific exploration across diverse facets. The implementation of easily accessible diagnostic facilities in proximity and genetic testing for pharmacogenomics to enhance prognoses would also aid in mitigating the burden and advancing the healthcare system's effectiveness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Population Based Cancer Registry (PBCR) was supported by National Centre for Disease Informatics and Research (NCDIR) of the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR), India.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zomawia</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Health Mission, Department of Health &amp; Family Welfare, Government of Mizoram, Dinthar, 796009, Aizawl, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zami</LastName><ForeName>Zothan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Mizoram University, Aizawl, 796004, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vanlallawma</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Mizoram University, Aizawl, 796004, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Nachimuthu Senthil</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Mizoram University, Aizawl, 796004, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zothanzama</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Mizoram University, Aizawl, 796004, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tlau</LastName><ForeName>Lalchhanhimi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Civil Hospital Aizawl, Department of Health &amp; Family Welfare, Government of Mizoram, Dawrpui, 796001, Aizawl, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chhakchhuak</LastName><ForeName>Lalchhandama</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Civil Hospital Aizawl, Department of Health &amp; Family Welfare, Government of Mizoram, Dawrpui, 796001, Aizawl, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pachuau</LastName><ForeName>Lalawmpuii</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Civil Hospital Aizawl, Department of Health &amp; Family Welfare, Government of Mizoram, Dawrpui, 796001, Aizawl, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pautu</LastName><ForeName>Jeremy L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Mizoram State Cancer Institute, Zemabawk, 796017, Aizawl, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hmangaihzuali</LastName><ForeName>Evelyn V L</ForeName><Initials>EVL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Population Based Cancer Registry Mizoram, NCDIR (ICMR), Civil Hospital Aizawl, Department of Health &amp; Family Welfare, Government of Mizoram, Dawrpui, 796001, Aizawl, Mizoram, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Reg Health Southeast Asia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918419282806676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2772-3682</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer incidence &amp; mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endogamous</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health care systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mizoram</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Northeast India</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37780980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10541469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lansea.2023.100281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2772-3682(23)00141-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sailo C.V., Tonsing M.V., Sanga Z., et al. Risk factors of tuberculosis in Mizoram: first report of the possible role of water source. Indian J Tuberc. 2022;69(4):675&#x2013;681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36460407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Census of India 2011, Government of India. https://www.censusindia.co.in/states/mizoram</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forest Survey of India Ministry of environment, forest &amp; climate change. https://fsi.nic.in/cover_2011/mizoram.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pachuau L., Zami Z., Nunga T., et al. First-degree family history of cancer can be a potential risk factor among head and neck cancer patients in an isolated Mizo tribal population, northeast India. Clin Epidemiol Glob Health. 2022;13</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Centre for Disease Informatics and Research  Consolidated report of population based cancer registries, 2006-2008, 2009-2011, 2012-2014, Bengaluru, India, National Cancer Registry Programme (NCRP-ICMR) https://ncdirindia.org/Reports.aspx</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Report of National cancer registry Programme (2012-2016) Bangaluru; India: 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma J.D., Kalit M., Nirmolia T., Saikia S.P., Sharma A., Barman D. Cancer: scenario and relationship of different geographical areas of the globe with special reference to North East-India. Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2014;15(8):3721&#x2013;3729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24870783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omran A.R. The epidemiologic transition. A theory of the epidemiology of population change. Milbank Mem Fund Q. 1971;49:509&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5155251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gersten O., Wilmoth J.R. The cancer transition in Japan since 1951. Demogr Res. 2002;7:271&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E., Altman D.G., Egger M., et al. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Lancet. 2007;370(9596):1453&#x2013;1457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18064739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO: international statistical classification of diseases and related health problems. World Health Organization; Geneva, Switzerland: 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segi M. The Department of Public Health, Tohoku University School of Medicine; 1960. Cancer mortality for selected sites in 24 countries 1950-1957. Sendai, Japan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joinpoint Regression Program, version 4.9.1.0; Statistical Methodology and Applications Branch, Surveillance Research Program. National Cancer Institute; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H.J., Fay M.P., Feuer E.J., Midthune D.N. Permutation tests for Joinpoint regression with applications to cancer rates. Stat Med. 2000;19:335&#x2013;351. (correction: 2001; 20: 655)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10649300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flourish Studio Kiln enterprises Ltd. 2020. https://flourish.studio/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanker N., Mathur P., Das P., Sathishkumar K., Martina Shalini A.J., Chaturvedi M. Cancer scenario in North-East India &amp; need for an appropriate research agenda. Indian J Med Res. 2021;154(1):27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34782528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>India State-Level Disease Burden Initiative Cancer Collaborators The burden of cancers and their variations across the states of India: the Global Burden of Disease Study 1990-2016. Lancet Oncol. 2018;19(10):1289&#x2013;1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6167407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30219626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferlay J., Curado M.P., Edwards B., et al. IARC Scientific publications No. 160; Lyon, IARC: 2007. Cancer incidence in five continents, VOL. IX.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulothungan V., Sathishkumar K., Leburu S., et al. Burden of cancers in India&#x2013;estimates of cancer crude incidence, YLLs, YLDs and DALYs for 2021 and 2025 based on National Cancer Registry Program. BMC Cancer. 2022;22:527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9092762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35546232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghatak S., Chakraborty P., Sarkar S.R., et al. Novel APC gene mutations associated with protein alteration in diffuse type gastric cancer. BMC Med Genet. 2017;18:61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5457612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28576136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghatak S., Lalnunhlimi S., Lalrohlui F., et al. Novel AKT1 mutations associated with cell-cycle abnormalities in gastric carcinoma. Per Med. 2018;15(2):79&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29714127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalrohlui F., Zohmingthanga J., Hruaii V., Vanlallawma A., Kumar N.S. Whole exome sequencing identifies the novel putative gene variants related with type 2 diabetes in Mizo population, northeast India. Gene. 2021;769</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33059026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty P., Ghatak S., Yadav R., et al. Novel somatic mutations of the CDH1 gene associated with gastric cancer: prediction of pathogenicity using comprehensive in silico methods. Curr Pharmacogenomics Person Med. 2020;17(1):182&#x2013;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanlallawma A., Zami Z., Pautu J.L., et al. Pediatric leukemia could be driven predominantly by non-synonymous variants in mitochondrial complex V in Mizo population from Northeast India. Mitochondrial DNA A DNA Mapp Seq Anal. 2020;31(6):245&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32609037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanlallawma A., Lallawmzuali D., Pautu J.L., Scaria V., Sivasubbu S., Kumar N.S. Whole exome sequencing of pediatric leukemia reveals a novel InDel within FLT-3 gene in AML patient from Mizo tribal population, Northeast India. BMC Genom Data. 2022;23(1):23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35350997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hariprakash J.M., Vellarikkal S.K., Keechilat P., et al. Pharmacogenetic landscape of DPYD variants in south Asian populations by integration of genome-scale data. Pharmacogenomics. 2018;19(3):227&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29239269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zodinpuii D., Pautu J.L., Zothankima B., Pachuau L., Kumar N.S. Clinical features and first-degree relative breast cancer, their correlation with histological tumor grade: a 5-year retrospective case study of breast cancer in Mizoram, India. Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2020;27(2):1991&#x2013;2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31768959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferlay J., Ervik M., Lam F., et al.   International Agency for Research on Cancer; Lyon, France: 2020. Global cancer observatory: cancer today.https://gco.iarc.fr/today Available from:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong M.C.S., Huang J., Chan P.S.F., et al. Global incidence and mortality of gastric cancer, 1980-2018. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(7):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34309666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phukan R.K., Narain K., Zomawia E., Hazarika N.C., Mahanta J. Dietary habits and stomach cancer in Mizoram, India. J&#xa0;Gastroenterol. 2006;41(5):418&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16799882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalrohlui F., Ghatak S., Zohmingthanga J., Hruaii V., Kumar N.S. Fermented pork fat (Sa-um) and lifestyle risk factors as potential indicators for type 2 diabetes among the Mizo population, Northeast India. J&#xa0;Health Popul Nutr. 2021;40(1):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8296625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34294154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapa S., Lalrohlui F., Ghatak S., et al. Mitochondrial complex I and V gene polymorphisms associated with breast cancer in mizo-mongloid population. Breast Cancer. 2016;23(4):607&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25896597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zodinpuii D., Pautu J.L., Zothankima B., et al. Breast cancer is significantly associated with cancers in the first- and second-degree relatives in ethnic mizo-mongoloid population, Northeast India. Natl J Community Med. 2022;13(9):606&#x2013;611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar A., Bora D., Borthakur S.K., Goswami N.K., Saharia D. Wild edible plant resources used by the Mizos of Mizoram, India. Kathmandu University. J&#xa0;Sci Eng Technol. 2013;9(1):106&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalthanpuii P.B., Lalruatfela B., Zoramdinthara L.H. Traditional food processing techniques of the Mizo people of Northeast India. Sci Vis. 2015;15(1):39&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farvid M.S., Sidahmed E., Spence N.D., et al. Consumption of red meat and processed meat and cancer incidence: a systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective studies. Eur J Epidemiol. 2021;36:937&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34455534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Oliveira Mota J., Bou&#xe9; G., Guillou S., Pierre F., Membr&#xe9; J.M. Estimation of the burden of disease attributable to red meat consumption in France: influence on colorectal cancer and cardiovascular diseases. Food Chem Toxicol. 2019;130:174&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31103738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty P., Ghatak S., Chenkual S., et al. Panel of significant risk factors predicts early stage gastric cancer and indication of poor prognostic association with pathogens and microsatellite stability. Genes Environ. 2021;43(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33568233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav R.P., Ghatak S., Chakraborty P., et al. Lifestyle chemical carcinogens associated with mutations in cell cycle regulatory genes increases the susceptibility to gastric cancer risk. Environ Sci Pollut Res Int. 2018;25(31):31691&#x2013;31704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S., Madathil S.A., Ghatak S., et al. Association of tobacco smoke&#x2013;infused water (tuibur) use by Mizo people and risk of Helicobacter pylori infection. Environ Sci Pollut Res. 2020;27(8):8580&#x2013;8585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31904095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawla P., Barsouk A. Epidemiology of gastric cancer: global trends, risk factors and prevention. Prz Gastroenterol. 2019;14(1):26&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6444111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leemans C.R., Snijders P.J.F., Brakenhoff R.H. The molecular landscape of head and neck cancer. Nat Rev Cancer. 2018;18(5):269&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29497144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss A., Hashibe M., Chuang S.C., et al. Cigarette, cigar, and pipe smoking and the risk of head and neck cancers: pooled analysis in the international head and neck cancer epidemiology consortium. Am J Epidemiol. 2013;178(5):679&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3755640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23817919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Institute for Population Sciences (IIPS) and ICF . IIPS; Mumbai: 2021. National family health survey (NFHS-5), India, 2019-21: Mizoram.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonsing M.V., Ghatak S., Lalrohlui F., Kumar N.S., Zohmingthanga J. Five year record on cancer incidence from a diagnostic centre in Mizoram, Northeast India. Cancer Health Disparities. 2019;3:e1&#x2013;e15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi A.K., Kumar P., Bhandari M., Devnani B., Rath G.K. Burden of preventable cancers in India: time to strike the cancer epidemic. J&#xa0;Egypt Natl Canc Inst. 2017;29(1):11&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27591115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorthy B., Chu C., Carlin D.J. Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons: from metabolism to lung cancer. Toxicol Sci. 2015;145(1):5&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4408964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25911656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Report on monitoring survey of cancer risk factors and health system response in North East Region (NER) https://ncdirindia.org/All_Reports/ner2022/Mizoram.aspx</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang T.A., Wu P.F., Ko Y.C. Prevention of exposure to mutagenic fumes produced by hot cooking oil in Taiwanese kitchens. Environ Mol Mutagen. 1998;31(1):92&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C., Gao Y.T., Xiang Y.B., et al. Home kitchen ventilation, cooking fuels, and lung cancer risk in a prospective cohort of never smoking women in Shanghai, China. Int J Cancer. 2015;136(3):632&#x2013;638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4232458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24917360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T.Y., Fang Y.H., Chen H.L., et al. Impact of cooking oil fume exposure and fume extractor use on lung cancer risk in non-smoking Han Chinese women. Sci Rep. 2020;10:6774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7174336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korsiak J., Pinault L., Christidis T., Burnett R.T., Abrahamowicz M., Weichenthal S. Long-term exposure to wildfires and cancer incidence in Canada: a population-based observational cohort study. Lancet Planet Health. 2022;6(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35550079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ICMR-NCDIR . Bengaluru; India: 2021. Profile of cancer and related health indicators in the North East region of India.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngaihte P., Zomawia E., Kaushik I. Cancer in the NorthEast India: where we are and what needs to be done? Indian J Public Health. 2019;63:251&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31552857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaiphei S.D., Sisodia D.S. Terminal cancer in Northeast India: an analytical study on its rapid growth, causes and solutions. Eur J Res. 2020;6(3):248&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rassy E., Assi T., Pavlidis N. Exploring the biological hallmarks of cancer of unknown primary: where do we stand today? Br J Cancer. 2020;122(8):1124&#x2013;1132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32042068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>