<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37795760</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hematological oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hematol Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Expression of "DNA damage response" pathway genes in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma: The potential for exploiting synthetic lethality.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/hon.3225</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL) and follicular lymphoma (FL) are two of the most prevalent non-Hodgkin's lymphoma subtypes. Despite advances, treatment resistance and patient relapse remain challenging issues. Our study aimed to scrutinize gene expression distinctions between DLBCL and FL, employing a cohort of 53 DLBCL and 104 FL samples that underwent rigorous screening for genetic anomalies. The NanoString nCounter assay evaluated 730 cancer-associated genes, focusing on densely tumorous areas in diagnostic samples. Employing the Lymph2Cx method, we determined the cell-of-origin (COO) for DLBCL cases. Our meticulous analysis, facilitated by Qlucore Omics Explorer software, unveiled a substantial 37% of genes with significantly differential expression patterns between DLBCL and FL, pointing to nuanced mechanistic disparities. Investigating the impact of FL disease stage and DLBCL COO on gene expression yielded minimal differences, prompting us to direct our attention to consistently divergent genes in DLBCL. Intriguingly, our Gene Set Enrichment Analysis spotlighted 21% of these divergent genes, converging on the DNA damage response (DDR) pathway, vital for cell survival and cancer evolution. Strong positive correlations among most DDR genes were noted, with key genes like BRCA1, FANCA, FEN1, PLOD1, PCNA, and RAD51 distinctly upregulated in DLBCL compared to FL and normal tissue controls. These findings were subsequently validated using RNA seq data on normal controls and DLBCL samples from public databases like The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA) and the Genotype-Tissue Expression (GTEx) databases, enhancing the robustness of our results. Considering the established significance of these DDR genes in solid cancer therapies, our study underscores their potential applicability in DLBCL treatment strategies. In conclusion, our investigation highlights marked gene expression differences between DLBCL and FL, with particular emphasis on the essential DDR pathway. The identification of these DDR genes as potential therapeutic targets encourages further exploration of synthetic lethality-based approaches for managing DLBCL.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Hematological Oncology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mansoor</LastName><ForeName>Adnan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of Calgary, and Alberta Precision Laboratories (APL), Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamran</LastName><ForeName>Hamza</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of Calgary, and Alberta Precision Laboratories (APL), Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rizwan</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of Calgary, and Alberta Precision Laboratories (APL), Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akhter</LastName><ForeName>Ariz</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of Calgary, and Alberta Precision Laboratories (APL), Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roshan</LastName><ForeName>Tariq Mahmood</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of Calgary, and Alberta Precision Laboratories (APL), Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shabani-Rad</LastName><ForeName>Meer-Taher</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of Calgary, and Alberta Precision Laboratories (APL), Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bavi</LastName><ForeName>Prashant</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, University of Calgary, and Alberta Precision Laboratories (APL), Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stewart</LastName><ForeName>Douglas</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Calgary, Tom Baker Cancer Centre, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>25999</GrantID><Agency>Alberta Cancer Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Hematol Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8307268</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0278-0232</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DDR genes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diffuse large B-cell lymphoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">expression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">follicular lymphoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synthetic lethality</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37795760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hon.3225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Shankland KR, Armitage JO, Hancock BW. Non-Hodgkin lymphoma.&#xa0;Lancet. 2012;380(9844):848-857. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(12)60605-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gisselbrecht C, Glass B, Mounier N, et&#xa0;al. Salvage regimens with autologous transplantation for relapsed large B-cell lymphoma in the rituximab era. J Clin Oncol. 2010;28(27):4184-4190. https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2010.28.1618</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenz G, Staudt LM. Aggressive lymphomas. N Engl J Med. 2010;362(15):1417-1429. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmra0807082</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devan J, Janikova A, Mraz M. New concepts in follicular lymphoma&#xa0;biology: from BCL2 to epigenetic regulators and non-coding RNAs. Semin Oncol. 2018;45(5-6):291-302. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.seminoncol.2018.07.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman A, Jacobsen E. Follicular lymphoma: 2020 update on diagnosis and management. Am J Hematol. 2020;95(3):316-327. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajh.25696</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okosun J, B&#xf6;d&#xf6;r C, Wang J, et&#xa0;al. Integrated genomic analysis identifies recurrent mutations and evolution patterns driving the initiation and progression of follicular lymphoma. Nat Genet. 2014;46(2):176-181. https://doi.org/10.1038/ng.2856</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasqualucci L, Dalla-Favera R. Genetics of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. Blood. 2018;131(21):2307-2319. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2017-11-764332</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuvvula S, Dahiya S, Patel SA. The novel therapeutic landscape for relapsed/refractory diffuse large B cell lymphoma. Clin Lymphoma, Myeloma &amp; Leukemia. 2022;22(6):362-372. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clml.2021.11.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeijmakers JH. Genome maintenance mechanisms for preventing cancer. Nature. 2001;411(6835):366-374. https://doi.org/10.1038/35077232</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson SP, Bartek J. The DNA-damage response in human biology and disease. Nature. 2009;461(7267):1071-1078. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature08467</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanahan D, Weinberg RA. Hallmarks of cancer: the next generation. Cell. 2011;144(5):646-674. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2011.02.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curtin NJ. DNA repair dysregulation from cancer driver to therapeutic target. Nat Rev Cancer. 2012;12(12):801-817. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrc3399</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaelin WG, Jr. The concept of synthetic lethality in the context of anticancer therapy. Nat Rev Cancer. 2005;5(9):689-698. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrc1691</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant HE, Schultz N, Thomas HD, et&#xa0;al. Specific killing of BRCA2-deficient tumours with inhibitors of poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase. Nature. 2005;434(7035):913-917. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature03443</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashworth A, Lord CJ. Synthetic lethal therapies for cancer: what's next after PARP inhibitors? Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2018;15(9):564-576. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41571-018-0055-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Neil NJ, Bailey ML, Hieter P. Synthetic lethality and cancer. Nat Rev Genet. 2017;18(10):613-623. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrg.2017.47</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapuy B, Stewart C, Dunford AJ, et&#xa0;al. Molecular subtypes of diffuse large B cell lymphoma are associated with distinct pathogenic mechanisms and outcomes. Nat Med. 2018;24(5):679-690. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-018-0016-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson WH, Young RM, Schmitz R, et&#xa0;al. Targeting B cell receptor signaling with ibrutinib in diffuse large B cell lymphoma. Nat Med. 2015;21(8):922-926. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm.3884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasmahapatra G, Patel H, Dent P, Fisher RI, Friedberg J, Grant S. The Bruton tyrosine kinase (BTK) inhibitor PCI-32765 synergistically increases proteasome inhibitor activity in diffuse large-B cell lymphoma (DLBCL) and mantle cell lymphoma (MCL) cells sensitive or resistant to bortezomib. Br J Haematol. 2013;161(1):43-56. https://doi.org/10.1111/bjh.12206</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson WH, Wright GW, Huang DW, et&#xa0;al. Effect of ibrutinib with R-CHOP chemotherapy in genetic subtypes of DLBCL. Cancer Cell. 2021;39(12):1643-1653. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccell.2021.10.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swerdlow SH, Campo E, Pileri SA, et&#xa0;al. The 2016 revision of the World Health Organization classification of lymphoid neoplasms. Blood. 2016;127(20):2375-2390. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2016-01-643569</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott DW, Wright GW, Williams PM, et&#xa0;al. Determining cell-of-origin subtypes of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma using gene expression in formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded tissue. Blood. 2014;123(8):1214-1217. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2013-11-536433</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Z, Kang B, Li C, Chen T, Zhang Z. GEPIA2: an enhanced web server for large-scale expression profiling and interactive analysis. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47(W1):W556-w560. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkz430</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tutt ANJ, Garber JE, Kaufman B, et&#xa0;al. Adjuvant olaparib for patients with BRCA1-or BRCA2-mutated breast cancer. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(25):2394-2405. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa2105215</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F, Hu Z, Guo Z. Small-molecule inhibitors targeting FEN1 for cancer therapy. Biomolecules. 2022;12(7):1007. https://doi.org/10.3390/biom12071007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gola M, Stefaniak P, Godlewski J, Jereczek-Fossa BA, Starzy&#x144;ska A. Prospects of POLD1 in human cancers: a review. Cancers (Basel). 2023;15(6):1905. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers15061905</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li CM, Haratipour P, Lingeman RG, et&#xa0;al. Novel peptide therapeutic approaches for cancer treatment. Cells. 2021;10(11):2908. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells10112908</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JO, Kang MJ, Byun WS, et&#xa0;al. Metformin overcomes resistance to cisplatin in triple-negative breast cancer (TNBC) cells by targeting RAD51. Breast Cancer Res. 2019;21(1):115. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13058-019-1204-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susanibar-Adaniya S, Barta SK. Update on Diffuse large B cell lymphoma: a review of current data and potential applications on risk stratification and management. Am J Hematol. 2021. 2021;96(5):617-629. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajh.26151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coiffier B, Lepage E, Briere J, et&#xa0;al. CHOP chemotherapy plus rituximab compared with CHOP alone in elderly patients with diffuse large-B-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2002;346(4):235-242. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa011795</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le DT, Durham JN, Smith KN, et&#xa0;al. Mismatch repair deficiency predicts response of solid tumors to PD-1 blockade. Science. 2017;357(6349):409-413. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aan6733</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farmer H, McCabe N, Lord CJ, et&#xa0;al. Targeting the DNA repair defect in BRCA mutant cells as a therapeutic strategy. Nature. 2005;434(7035):917-921. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature03445</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Zhang Y, Wang X, Zhang L, Xu S. Construction and validation of an aging-related gene signature predicting the prognosis of pancreatic cancer. Front Genet. 2023;14:1022265. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2023.1022265</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang WH, Forde D, Lai AG. Dual prognostic role of 2-oxoglutarate-dependent oxygenases in ten cancer types: implications for cell cycle regulation and cell adhesion maintenance. Cancer Commun. 2019;39(1). https://doi.org/10.1186/s40880-019-0369-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paradiso A, Rabinovich M, Vallejo C, et&#xa0;al. p53 and PCNA expression in advanced colorectal cancer: response to chemotherapy and long-term prognosis. Int J Cancer. 1996;69(6):437-441. https://doi.org/10.1002/(sici)1097-0215(19961220)69:6&lt;437::aid-ijc2&gt;3.0.co;2-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Zou BJ, Zhao JZ, et&#xa0;al. A novel DNA damage repair-related signature for predicting prognositc and treatment response in non-small lung cancer. Front Oncol. 2022;12:961274. https://doi.org/10.3389/fonc.2022.961274</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy A, Zhang J, Davis NS, et&#xa0;al. Genetic and functional drivers of diffuse large B cell lymphoma. Cell. 2017;171(2):481-494.e415. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2017.09.027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz R, Wright GW, Huang DW, et&#xa0;al. Genetics and pathogenesis of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(15):1396-1407. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1801445</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo AR, Hav M, Singh M, et&#xa0;al. Single-cell spatial analysis of tumor immune architecture in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. Blood Adv. 2022;6(16):4675-4690. https://doi.org/10.1182/bloodadvances.2022007493</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye X, Wang L, Nie M, et&#xa0;al. A single-cell atlas of diffuse large B cell lymphoma. Cell Rep. 2022;39(3):110713. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2022.110713</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knittel G, Rehk&#xe4;mper T, Korovkina D, et&#xa0;al. Two mouse models reveal an actionable PARP1 dependence in aggressive chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Nat Commun. 2017;8(1):153. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-017-00210-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Zhou D, Wang L, Zhu L, Ye X. MYD88(L265P) and CD79B double mutations type (MCD type) of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma: mechanism, clinical characteristics, and targeted therapy. Ther Adv Hematol. 2022;13:20406207211072839. https://doi.org/10.1177/20406207211072839</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rendleman J, Antipin Y, Reva B, et&#xa0;al. Genetic variation in DNA repair pathways and risk of non-Hodgkin's lymphoma. PLoS One. 2014;9(7):e101685. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0101685</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Miranda NF, Peng R, Georgiou K, et&#xa0;al. DNA repair genes are selectively mutated in diffuse large B cell lymphomas. J Exp Med. 2013;210(9):1729-1742. https://doi.org/10.1084/jem.20122842</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Liu X, Chang Y, et&#xa0;al. Identification and validation of a DNA damage repair-related signature for diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. BioMed Res Int. 2022;2022. https://doi.org/10.1155/2022/2645090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi A, Orecchioni S, Falvo P, et&#xa0;al. Dual targeting of the DNA damage response pathway and BCL-2 in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma. Leukemia. 2022;36(1):197-209. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41375-021-01347-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein HL. The consequences of Rad51 overexpression for normal and tumor cells. DNA Repair (Amst). 2008;7(5):686-693. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dnarep.2007.12.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davids MS, Roberts AW, Seymour JF, et&#xa0;al. Phase I first-in-human study of venetoclax in patients with relapsed or refractory non-Hodgkin lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2017;35(8):826-833. https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2016.70.4320</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J, Isik E, Fernandes SM, Brown JR, Letai A, Davids MS. Bruton's tyrosine kinase inhibition increases BCL-2 dependence and enhances sensitivity to venetoclax in chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Leukemia. 2017;31(10):2075-2084. https://doi.org/10.1038/leu.2017.32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Gan S, Ren L, et&#xa0;al. Multifaceted regulation and functions of replication factor C family in human cancers. Am J Cancer Res. 2018;8(8):1343-1355.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyraud F, Italiano A. Combined PARP inhibition and immune checkpoint therapy in solid tumors. Cancers (Basel). 2020;12(6):1502. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers12061502</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceccaldi R, Rondinelli B, D'Andrea AD. Repair pathway choices and consequences at the double-strand break. Trends Cell Biol. 2016;26(1):52-64. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tcb.2015.07.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lord CJ, Ashworth A. PARP inhibitors: synthetic lethality in the clinic. Science. 2017;355(6330):1152-1158. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aam7344</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J, Sun D, Zhou H, Zhu J, Zhang X, Hou H. Next-generation sequencing identifies potential novel therapeutic targets in Chinese HGSOC patients. Pathol Res Pract. 2022;238:154074. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prp.2022.154074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JY, Zou T, Yin JY, et&#xa0;al. Genetic variants in double-strand break repair pathway genes to predict platinum-based chemotherapy prognosis in patients with lung cancer. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:915822. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2022.915822</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaina B, Christmann M. DNA repair in personalized brain cancer therapy with temozolomide and nitrosoureas. DNA Repair (Amst). 2019;78:128-141. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dnarep.2019.04.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vodicka P, Urbanova M, Makovicky P, et&#xa0;al. Oxidative damage in sporadic colorectal cancer: molecular mapping of base excision repair glycosylases in colorectal cancer patients. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(7):2473. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21072473</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>