<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37805963</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hematological oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hematol Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Revisiting the predictive role of 18F-fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography/computerized tomography on treatment outcome in early-stage favorable Hodgkin lymphoma.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>608</StartPage><EndPage>611</EndPage><MedlinePgn>608-611</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/hon.3158</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the present manuscript Gallamini et al. comment the results of three large, phase III, randomized clinical trials in early-stage favorable Hodgkin Lymphoma (HL), aimed at exploring the non-inferiority of ABVD chemotherapy alone compared to combined-modality treatment with ABVD and Involved Field/Node Radiotherapy (INRT). The authors also report the preliminary results of risk-stratification in the first 60 enrolled patients in the phase 2, prospective, international study RAFTING: RAdiotherapy Free Treatment IN Good-prognosis early-stage HL (National Trial Identifier 04866654). In this trial patients are stratified, before treatment onset, according to the risk of therapy failure in a single patient basis, taking into account non only the results of interim and End-of-Therapy PET, but also the value of new metrics extracted from the baseline PET/CT such as the Large Nodal Mass (LNM) and Total Metabolic Tumor Volume (TMTV). Treatment intensity, consisting in ABVD chemotherapy, INRT and Nivolumab maintenance, is modulated on the presence/absence of the above factors, in a personalized-medicine approach. The most frequently detected factors driving treatment intensity were LNM and TMTV, while the results of interim and end-of-treatment PET were also determinant, albeit in a lower percentage of cases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Hematological Oncology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gallamini</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2054-7412</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Onco-Hematology Department, A. Lacassagne Cancer Center, Nice, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sudria</LastName><ForeName>Axel</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0244-5404</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Onco-Hematology Department, A. Lacassagne Cancer Center, Nice, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurlapski</LastName><ForeName>Micha&#x142;</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hematology and Bone Marrow Transplantation - Gdansk University, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gastaud</LastName><ForeName>Lauris</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Onco-Hematology Department, A. Lacassagne Cancer Center, Nice, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Hematol Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8307268</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0278-0232</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Large Nodal Mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Total Metabolic Tumor Volume</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">baseline PET</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">end-of-therapy PET</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interim PET</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37805963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hon.3158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen FE, Ng AK. Long-term risk of second malignancy and cardiovascular disease after Hodgkin lymphoma treatment. Hematology Am Soc Hematol Educ Program. 2016;1:323-330. https://doi.org/10.1182/asheducation-2016.1.323</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansell SM. Hodgkin lymphoma: 2016 update on diagnosis, risk-stratification, and management. Am J Hematol. 2016;91(4):434-442. https://doi.org/10.1002/AJH.24272</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaapveld M, Aleman BM, van Eggermond AM, et&#xa0;al. Second cancer risk up to 40 years after treatment for Hodgkin's Lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2015;373(26):2499-2511. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1505949</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel G, Michaelson E, Chen YH, et&#xa0;al. Reduced mortality risk in the recent era in early-stage Hodgkin lymphoma patients treated with radiation therapy with or without chemotherapy. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2018;100(2):498-506. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrobp.2017.09.048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radford J, Illidge T, Counsell N, et&#xa0;al. Results of a trial of PET-directed therapy for early-stage Hodgkin&#x2019;s lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2015;372(17):1598-1607. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1408648</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xe9; MPE, Girinsky T, Federico M, et&#xa0;al. Early positron emission tomography response-adapted treatment in stage I and II Hodgkin lymphoma: final results of the randomized EORTC/LYSA/FIL H10 trial. J Clin Oncol. 2017;35(16):1786-1794. https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2016.68.6394</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raemaekers JMM, Andr&#xe9; MPE, Federico M, et&#xa0;al. Omitting radiotherapy in early positron emission tomography-negative stage I/II Hodgkin lymphoma is associated with an increased risk of early relapse: clinical results of the preplanned interim analysis of the randomized EORTC/LYSA/FIL H10 trial. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(12):1188-1194. https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2013.51.9298</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs M, Goergen H, Kobe C, et&#xa0;al. Positron emission tomography-guided treatment in early-stage favorable Hodgkin lymphoma: final results of the international, randomized phase III HD16 trial by the German Hodgkin Study Group. J Clin Oncol. 2019;37(31):2835-2845. https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.19.00964</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchings M, Loft A, Hansen M, et&#xa0;al. FDG-PET after two cycles of chemotherapy predicts treatment failure and progression-free survival in Hodgkin lymphoma. Blood. 2006;107(1):52-59. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2005-06-2252</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straus DJ, Johnson JL, LaCasce AS, et&#xa0;al. Doxorubicin, vinblastine, and gemcitabine (CALGB 50203) for stage I/II nonbulky Hodgkin lymphoma: pretreatment prognostic factors and interim PET. Blood. 2011;117(20):5314-5320. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2010-10-314260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallamini A, Picardi M, Et al. T021: Radiation-Free Therapy as the INitial treatment of Good-prognosis early non-bulky Hodgkin lymphoma, defined by a low Metabolic Tumor Volume and a negative PET-2 - RAFTING Trial. HemaSphere. 2022;6:10-11. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.hs9.0000890652.56016.97</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes JA, LaCasce AS, Zukotynski K, et&#xa0;al. End-of treatment but not interim PET scan predicts outcome in nonbulky limited-stage Hodgkin&#x2019;s lymphoma. Ann Oncol. 2011;22(4):910-915. https://doi.org/10.1093/annonc/mdq549</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciammella P, Filippi AR, Simontacchi G, et&#xa0;al. Post-ABVD/pre-radiotherapy 18F-FDG-PET provides additional prognostic information for early-stage Hodgkin lymphoma: a retrospective analysis on 165 patients. Br J Radiol. 2016;89(1061):20150983. https://doi.org/10.1259/bjr.20150983</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>