<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37806994</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-0832</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Mycopathologia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mycopathologia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Diagnostic Utility of Galactomannan Enzyme Immunoassay in Invasive Aspergillosis in Pediatric patients with Hematological Malignancy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11046-023-00798-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aims to determine the diagnostic utility of galactomannan enzyme immunoassay (GM EIA) in invasive aspergillosis (IA) in children with hematological malignancy (high risk population) in terms of sensitivity, specificity, negative predictive value (NPV) and positive predictive values (PPV) at various cut offs while validating the revised EORTC/MSG 2019 criteria in order to obtain the best cut-off.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">For 100 pediatric patients, serum and respiratory samples were collected. Clinical, mycological workup (potassium-hydroxide mount, fungal culture) and GM EIA was done to classify proven, probable, and possible IA as per EORTC-MSG guidelines,2019. Sensitivity, specificity, PPV and NPV were calculated of GM indices at cut-off 0.5, 0.7 and 1, and validated with revised EORTC -MSG, 2019.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 100 patients enrolled, 75 were diagnosed with ALL, 14 with AML, two with Hodgkin's, three had non-Hodgkin lymphoma, and six had undifferentiated leukemia. With routine mycological findings, 51 were classified as probable IA, 11 as possible IA, and 38 as no IA. Aspergillus flavus was the most prevalent on culture (56.9%, 29/51) followed by A. fumigatus (29%, 15/51) A. niger (7.8%, 4/51), A. terreus (3.9%, 2/51) and A. nidulans (2%, 1/51). GM EIA demonstrated sensitivity 82.3%, specificity 97.4%, PPV 98.1%, and NPV 77.1% at cut-off 0.67 when comparing probable/possible IA v/s no IA groups. The GM EIA had the best sensitivity (82.4%), specificity (81.8%), PPV (95.5%), and NPV (50%) at cut off 0.78 when the probable IA group was compared to the possible IA. Seven patients succumbed of whom 5 had GMI&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;2.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study deduces the optimal cut-off for serum GM EIA to be 0.67 obtained by ROC analysis when comparing possible and probable IA versus no IA and reinforces the definition of probable category of EORTC-MSG criteria, 2019. At 0.5 ODI the sensitivity (87.1%) and NPV (80.5%) are high, thus making it the most suitable cut-off for detecting true positive and ruling out IA respectively, in pediatric patients with hematological malignancy. GM EIA when performed adjunctive to clinico-radiological findings can prove to be screening, diagnostic and prognostic test for IA in pediatric hematological malignancy patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Das</LastName><ForeName>Sutapa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and Safdarjung Hospital, New Delhi, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Capoor</LastName><ForeName>Malini R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8423-0505</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and Safdarjung Hospital, New Delhi, Delhi, India. malinircapoor@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Amitabh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and Safdarjung Hospital, New Delhi, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwal</LastName><ForeName>Yatish</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vardhman Mahavir Medical College and Safdarjung Hospital, New Delhi, Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Mycopathologia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7505689</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0301-486X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GM cutoff for IA in high risk group</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Invasive aspergillosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pedriatric hematological malignancy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Serum galactomannan enzyme Immunoassay</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37806994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11046-023-00798-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11046-023-00798-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maschmeyer G, Haas A, Cornely OA. Invasive aspergillosis: epidemiology, diagnosis and management in immunocompromised patients. Drugs. 2007;67:1567&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00003495-200767110-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17661528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfaller MA, Diekema DJ. Epidemiology of invasive candidiasis: a persistent public health problem. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2007;20:133&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CMR.00029-06</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17223626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1797637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezgin M, T&#xfc;fek&#xe7;i &#xd6;, Baytan B, &#xd6;ren H, &#xc7;elebi S, Ener B, et al. Invasive fungal infections in children with leukemia: the clinical features and Prognosis. Turk J Haematol 2021,;94&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otto WR, Green AM. Fungal infections in children with haematologic malignancies and stem cell transplant recipients. Br J Haematol. 2020;189(4):607&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjh.16452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32159231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7231650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongomin F, Gago S, Oladele RO, Denning DW. Global and multi-national prevalence of fungal diseases-estimate precision. J Fungi. 2017;3:57&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jof3040057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global Action Fund for Fungal Infections (GAFFI). Priority fungal infections. Available online: http://www.gaffi.org/media/fact-sheets/ (accessed on 27 Jan 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozaliyani A, Sedono R, Jusuf A, Rumende C, Aniwidyaningsih W, Burhan E, et al. A novel diagnosis scoring model to predict invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in the intensive care unit. Saudi Med J. 2019;40:140&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15537/smj.2019.2.22940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30723858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6402463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly J, Chen S, Kauffman C, Steinbach W, Baddley J, Verweij P, et al. Revision and update of the consensus definitions of invasive fungal disease from the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer and the Mycoses study group education and research consortium. Clin Inf Dis. 2019;71:1367&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciz1008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiss E, Shadomy H, Lyon G. Aspergillosis fundamental medical mycology. NJ: Hoboken Wiley Blackwell; 2012; 357&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung L, Lange BJ, Gerbing RB, Alonzo TA, Feusner J. Microbiologically documented infections and infection-related mortality in children with acute myeloid leukemia. Blood. 2007;110:3532&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2007-05-091942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17660380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergidis P, et al. High-volume culture and quantitative real-time PCR for the detection of aspergillus in sputum&#x2019;. Clin Microbiol Inf. 2020;26(7):935&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2019.11.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tragiannidis A, et al. Invasive aspergillosis in children with acquired immunodeficiencies. Clin Inf Dis. 2011;54(2):258&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cir786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;a&#x11f;lar &#x130;, &#xd6;zkerim D, Tahta N, D&#xfc;zg&#xf6;l M, Bayram N, Demira&#x11f; B, et al. Assessment of serum galactomannan test results of pediatric patients with hematologic malignancies according to consecutive positivity and threshold level in terms of invasive aspergillosis diagnosis: cross-sectional research in a tertiary care hospital. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2019;42:e271&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPH.0000000000001653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha A, Bansal D, Chakrabarti A, Shivaprakash M, Trehan A, Marwaha R. Serum galactomannan assay for the diagnosis of invasive aspergillosis in children with hematological malignancies. Mycoses. 2013;56:442&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/myc.12048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23369047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avcu G, Karapinar D, Akinci A, Sivis Z, Sahin A, Bal Z, et al. Utility of the serum galactomannan assay for the diagnosis of invasive aspergillosis in children with acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Intern J Infect Dis. 2017;54:8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2016.10.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R, Singh C, Khadwal A, Prakash G, Malhotra P, Jain A, et al. Role of pre-transplant chest high-resolution computed tomography and serum galactomannan index in predicting post-transplant invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplant recipients. Transpl Infect Dis. 2021;23(4):e13632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tid.13632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33973316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraczek MG, et al. Volume dependency for culture of fungi from respiratory secretions and increased sensitivity of Aspergillus quantitative PCR. Mycoses. 2013;57(2):69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/myc.12103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23786547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinand V, Anjan M, Oberoi JK, Khanna S, Yadav SP, Wattal C, et al. Threshold of galactomannan antigenemia positivity for diagnosis of invasive aspergillosis in neutropenic children. J Microbiol Immunol Inf. 2016;49:66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmii.2013.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohindra R, Capoor MR, Puri S, Raheja H, Gupta DK, Gupta B, et al. Evaluation of serum galactomannan enzyme immunoassay at two different cut-offs for the diagnosis of invasive aspergillosis in patients with febrile neutropenia. Indian J Med Microbiol. 2017;35(2):237&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijmm.IJMM_17_47</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28681812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rdramurthy S, Paul R, Chakrabarti A, Mouton J, Meis J. Invasive aspergillosis by Aspergillus flavus: epidemiology, diagnosis, antifungal resistance, and management. J fungi. 2019;5:55&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jof5030055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maertens J, et al. Galactomannan serves as a surrogate endpoint for outcome of pulmonary invasive aspergillosis in Neutropenic Hematology patients. Cancer. 2008;115(2):355&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.24022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huppler AR, Fisher BT, Lehrnbecher T, Walsh TJ, Steinbach WJ. Role of molecular biomarkers in the diagnosis of invasive fungal diseases in children. J Pediatric Infect Dis Soc. 2017;6:32&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jpids/pix054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher BT, Zaoutis TE, Park JR, et al. Galactomannan antigen testing for diagnosis of invasive aspergillosis in pediatric hematology patients. J Pediatric Infect Dis Soc. 2012;1:103&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jpids/pis044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23687575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3656552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte RF, et al. Serum Galactomannan-based early detection of invasive aspergillosis in hematology patients receiving effective Antimold Prophylaxis. Clin Inf Dis. 2014;59(12):1696&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciu673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoo AL, et al. Cost-effectiveness of serum galactomannan surveillance during mould-active antifungal prophylaxis. J Fungi. 2021;7(6):417. https://doi.org/10.3390/jof7060417 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jof7060417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao W, et al. Sputum signatures for invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in patients with underlying respiratory diseases (SPARED): study protocol for a prospective diagnostic trial. BMC Inf Dis. 2018;18(1):4369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-018-3180-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luabeya AK, et al. Noninvasive detection of tuberculosis by oral swab analysis&#x2019;. J Clin Microbiol. 2019;57(3):10&#x2013;1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01847-18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercier T, Castagnola E, Marr KA, Wheat LJ, Verweij PE, Maertens JA. Defining Galactomannan positivity in the updated EORTC/MSGERC consensus definitions of invasive fungal diseases. Clin Inf Dis. 2021;72:S89-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciaa1786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han SB, Kim SK, Lee JW, Yoon J-S, Chung N-G, Cho B, et al. Serum Galactomannan index for early prediction of mortality in immunocompromised children with invasive pulmonary aspergillosis. BMC Inf Dis. 2015;15(1):15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-015-1014-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar J, Singh A, Seth R, Xess I, Kabra SK. Galactomannan Antigen Test for Early Diagnosis of Invasive Aspergillus Infection in Pediatric Febrile Neutropenia. Indian Pediatr. 2018;55(3):257&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13312-018-1329-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29629702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badiee P, Karimi M, Alborzi A, Pourabbas B, Shakiba E, Mardaneh J. Invasive aspergillosis in pediatric hematology oncology ward. Iran J Blood Cancer. 2010;2:67&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SH, Kang ES, Eo H, Yoo SY, Kim JH, Yoo KH, et al. Aspergillus galactomannan antigen assay and invasive aspergillosis in pediatric cancer patients and hematopoietic stem cell transplant recipients. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2013;60:31622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.24363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gefen A, Zaidman I, Shachor-Meyouhas Y, Avidor I, Hakim F, Weyl Ben-Arush M, et al. Serum galactomannan screening for diagnosis of invasive pulmonary aspergillosis in children after stem cell transplantation or with high-risk leukemia. Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2015;32(2):146&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/08880018.2014.981900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25569600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zen S, &#xd6;zdemir H, Evren E, Taskin EC, Arga G, Konca HC, et al. The role of galactomannan test results in the diagnosis of pediatric invasive aspergillosis. Infect Dis. 2022;54:269&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23744235.2021.2008486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>