<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37816985</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1435-1102</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archives of women's mental health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Womens Ment Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Socio-demographic determinants of intimate partner violence in Angola: a cross-sectional study&#xa0;of nationally representative survey data.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00737-023-01376-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Intimate Partner Violence (IPV) is a global problem of public health importance, which can be found across all social layers and cultural backgrounds worldwide. Angola is still an under-explored country in the context of domestic violence and was therefore chosen as our focus of interest. Our study's goal was to identify the socio-demographic determinants of IPV in Angola. We used nationally representative data from female respondents of the 2015 Angolan Demographic and Health Surveys (DHS). Simple bivariate and multiple logistic regression analyses were used to assess the relationship between the experience of IPV and the women's' individual and contextual characteristics. Out of the 7,699 respondents, 3,070 (41.1%) reported having experienced at least one form of violence by their partners, with physical violence being more prevalent (32.5%) than emotional (27.7%) and sexual violence (7.2%). The partner's use of alcohol, the respondent's tendency to hurt her partner, her having witnessed her father beating her mother and being the first wife showed significantly higher odds of experiencing one or more types of IPV, whereas being older than the partner appears to have protective effects. Our findings reflect the widespread prevalence rates of violence against women in African countries. Future intervention programs should focus on women with risky background characteristics to help decrease domestic abuse in Angola. Our results indicate to focus on young women who have witnessed domestic violence in childhood, those whose partners use alcohol and those who tend to physically hurt their partners themselves. It is also recommended to intensify future research on the effects of co-wives on a relationship since first wives were found to have a higher risk of being physically abused by their partners.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skandro</LastName><ForeName>Simona</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heidelberg Institute of Global Health (HIGH), University of Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abio</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heidelberg Institute of Global Health (HIGH), University of Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Injury Epidemiology and Prevention, Turku Brain Injury Center, Turku University Hospital and University of Turku, Turku, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baernighausen</LastName><ForeName>Till</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heidelberg Institute of Global Health (HIGH), University of Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lowery Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heidelberg Institute of Global Health (HIGH), University of Heidelberg, Heidelberg, Germany. michael.wilson@uni-heidelberg.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Austria</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Womens Ment Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9815663</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1434-1816</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Marriage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Violence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Women&#x2019;s health</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37816985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00737-023-01376-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00737-023-01376-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abramsky T, Watts CH, Garcia-Moreno C, Devries K, Kiss L, Ellsberg M, Jansen HAFM, Heise L (2011) What factors are associated with recent intimate partner violence? findings from the WHO multi-country study on women&#x2019;s health and domestic violence. BMC Public Health 11(1):109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-11-109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21324186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3049145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adebowale AS (2018) Spousal age difference and associated predictors of intimate partner violence in nigeria. BMC Public Health 18(1):212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-018-5118-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29394924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5797410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andarge E, Shiferaw Y (2018) Disparities in intimate partner violence among currently married women from food secure and insecure urban households in south ethiopia: A community based comparative cross-sectional study. BioMed Research International 1&#x2013;12:2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthi V, Fenske J (2018) Polygamy and child mortality: Historical and modern evidence from nigeria&#x2019;s igbo. Review of Economics of the Household 16(1):97&#x2013;141</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11150-016-9353-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benebo FO, Schumann B, Vaezghasemi M (2018) Intimate partner violence against women in nigeria: a multilevel study investigating the effect of women&#x2019;s status and community norms. BMC Women&#x2019;s Health 18(1):136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-018-0628-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30092785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6085661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bereczkei T, Gyuris P, Weisfeld GE (2004) Sexual imprinting in human mate choice. Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. Series B: Biological Sciences, 271(1544):1129&#x2013;1134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boerma JT, Sommerfelt AE (1993) Demographic and health surveys (DHS): contributions and limitations. World Health Stat Q 46(4):222&#x2013;226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8017081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonomi AE, Thompson RS, Anderson M, Reid RJ, Carrell D, Dimer JA, Rivara FP (2006) Intimate partner violence and women&#x2019;s physical, mental, and social functioning. American Journal of Preventive Medicine 30(6):458&#x2013;466</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2006.01.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16704938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bott S, Guedes A, Goodwin M, Mendoza J (2012) Violence Against Women in Latin America and the Caribbean: A Comparative Analysis of Population-Based Data from 12 Countries. PAHO 12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne K.P, Hamilton-Glachritsis C, Vettor S. The cycles of violence the relationship between childhood maltreatment and the risk of later becoming a victim or perpetrator of violence key facts</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capaldi DM, Knoble NB, Shortt JW, Kim HK (2012) A Systematic Review of Risk Factors for Intimate Partner Violence. Partner Abuse 3(2):231&#x2013;280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/1946-6560.3.2.231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22754606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3384540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coker AL (2000) Physical health consequences of physical and psychological intimate partner violence. Archives of Family Medicine 9(5):451&#x2013;457</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archfami.9.5.451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10810951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes LF, de&#xa0;Mello Padoin SM, Cardoso&#xa0;de Paula C, Vieira LB, Landerdahl MC, Bastos&#xa0;da Silva E (2013) Limitations and possibilities on health assessment to women in violence situation. Health 05(7):45&#x2013;51</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBruine LM, Jones BC, Little AC (2017) Positive sexual imprinting for human eye color</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domestic violence: An ongoing threat to women in latin america and the caribbean - population reference bureau, 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EIGE (2017) Glossary of definitions of rape, femicide and intimate partner violence. European Institute for Gender Equality. OCLC: 1044442576</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekerbicer HC, Resim S, Efe E, Bahar MR, Altunoren O, Kucukdurmaz F, Benlioglu C (2016) A comparison of sexual function, psychological status, and sociodemographic characteristics of turkish men within polygamous and monogamous marriages. Balkan Medical Journal 33(4):383&#x2013;389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5152/balkanmedj.2016.16459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27606132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5001814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fish E, DeBold J, Miczek K (2002) Repeated alcohol: behavioral sensitization and alcohol-heightened aggression in mice. Psychopharmacology 160(1):39&#x2013;48</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-001-0934-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11862372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freud S, Crick J (1999) The interpretation of dreams. Oxford University Press</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Moreno C, Pallitto C, Devries K, St&#xf6;ckl H, Watts C, Abrahams N (2013) Global and regional estimates of violence against women: prevalence and health effects of intimate partner violence and non-partner sexual violence. World Health Organization, OCLC: ocn875165997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber MR, Fried LE, Pineles SL, Shipherd JC, Bernstein CA (2012) Posttraumatic stress disorder and intimate partner violence in a women&#x2019;s headache center. Women &amp; Health 52(5):454&#x2013;471</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03630242.2012.684088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson MA, Mace R (2007) Polygyny, reproductive success and child health in rural ethiopia: Why marry a married man? Journal of Biosocial Science 39(2):287&#x2013;300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0021932006001441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16817989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Headey B, Scott D, Vaus DD (1999) Domestic violence in australia: Are women and men equally violent? Australian Social Monitor 2:57</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess KL, Javanbakht M, Brown JM, Weiss RE, Hsu P, Gorbach PM (2012) Intimate partner violence and sexually transmitted infections among young adult women. Sexually Transmitted Diseases 39(5):366&#x2013;371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/OLQ.0b013e3182478fa5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22504601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ICF Zambia Statistics&#xa0;Agency, Ministry of Health (MOH)&#xa0;Zambia (2019) 2018 zambia demographic health survey summary report</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institut National de la Statistique (INSTAT) and ICF (2019) 2018 mali demographic and health survey key findings</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismayilova L (2015) Spousal violence in 5 transitional countries: A population-based multilevel analysis of individual and contextual factors. American Journal of Public Health 105(11):e12&#x2013;e22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2015.302779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26378858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4605178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung CG (1915) The theory of psychoanalysis. Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease Pub. Co</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keyes KM, Hatzenbuehler ML, Grant BF, Hasin DS (2012) Stress and alcohol: epidemiologic evidence. Alcohol Research: Current Reviews 34(4):391&#x2013;400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23584105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Motsei M (2002) women enjoy punishment: attitudes and experiences of gender-based violence among PHC nurses in rural south africa. Social Science &amp; Medicine 54(8):1243&#x2013;1254</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0277-9536(01)00093-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenig MA, Stephenson R, Ahmed S, Jejeebhoy SJ, Campbell J (2006) Individual and contextual determinants of domestic violence in north india. American Journal of Public Health 96(1):132&#x2013;138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2004.050872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16317213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1470450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kringelbach HN (2016) marrying out for love: Women&#x2019;s narratives of polygyny and alternative marriage choices in contemporary senegal. African Studies Review 59(1):155&#x2013;174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/asr.2016.7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasong J, Zhang Y, Muyayalo KP, Njiri OA, Gebremedhin SA, Abaidoo CS, Liu CY, Zhang H, Zhao K (2020) Domestic violence among married women of reproductive age in zimbabwe: a cross sectional study. BMC Public Health 20(1):354</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-8447-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32183756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7079366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mammen K (2019) All for one or each for her own: Do polygamous families share andShare alike? Journal for the Advancement of Developing Economies</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SL (2005) Victims as offenders: The paradox of women&#x2019;s violence in relationships</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minist&#xe9;rio da Sa&#xfa;de&#xa0;(MINSA) Instituto Nacional&#xa0;de Estat&#xed;stica (2017) Minist&#xe9;rio da Planeamento e do Desenvolvimento Territorial (MPDT), and ICF. Inqu&#xe9;rito de indicadores m&#xfa;ltiplos e de sa&#xfa;de em angola 2015-16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell J, Wight M, Van Heerden A, Rochat TJ (2016) Intimate partner violence, HIV, and mental health: a triple epidemic of global proportions. International Review of Psychiatry 28(5):452&#x2013;463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09540261.2016.1217829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27599188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montesanti SR, Thurston WE (2015) Mapping the role of structural and interpersonal violence in the lives of women: implications for public health interventions and policy. BMC Women&#x2019;s Health 15(1):100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-015-0256-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26554358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4641364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Population Commission (NPC) [Nigeria] and ICF (2019) 2018 Nigeria DHS key findings</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogum Alangea D, Addo-Lartey AA, Sikweyiya Y, Chirwa ED, Coker-Appiah D, Jewkes R, Mawuena Kofi Adanu R (2018) Prevalence and risk factors of intimate partner violence among women in four districts of the central region of ghana: Baseline findings from a cluster randomised controlled trial. PLOS ONE 13(7):e0200874</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0200874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30024948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6053193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phaswana-Mafuya N, Shisana O, Davids A, Tabane C, Mbelle M, Matseke G, Banyini M, Kekana Q (2014) Perceptions of sugar mommy practices in South Africa. J. Psychol. Afr. 24(3):257&#x2013;263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14330237.2014.906086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25431532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4226421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders DG, Kurko JF, Barlow K, Crane CE (2011) What attracts men who batter to their partners? an exploratory study. Journal of Interpersonal Violence 26(14):2747&#x2013;2763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260510390943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugg N (2015) Intimate partner violence. Medical Clinics of North America 99(3):629&#x2013;649</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcna.2015.01.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25841604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan SC, Gambone LJ, Caldwell JE, Sullivan TP, Snow DL (2008) A review of research on women&#x2019;s use of violence with male intimate partners. Violence and Victims 23(3):301&#x2013;314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/0886-6708.23.3.301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18624096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2968709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tertilt M (2015) Polygyny, Fertility, and Savings. Journal of Political Economy</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson Klohnen, Casillas Nus Simms, Haig Berry (2004) Match Makers and Deal Breakers: Analyses of Assortative Mating in Newlywed Couples. Journal of Personality 72(5):1029&#x2013;1068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0022-3506.2004.00289.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15335336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wingood GM, DiClemente RJ (1997) The effects of an abusive primary partner on the condom use and sexual negotiation practices of african-american women. American Journal of Public Health 87(6):1016&#x2013;1018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.87.6.1016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9224187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1380941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (2018) Global, regional and national prevalence estimates for intimate partner violence against women and global and regional prevalence estimates for non-partner sexual violence against women. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240022256 . Accessed 4 Oct 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaya S, Ghose B (2018) Prevalence of unmet need for contraception and its association with unwanted pregnancy among married women in Angola. PLoS One 13(12):e0209801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0209801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30596733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6312300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaya S, Ghose B (2019) Alcohol drinking by husbands/partners is associated with higher intimate partner violence against women in angola. Safety 5(1):5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/safety5010005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>