<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37815282</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1535-1815</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pediatric emergency care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Emerg Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical Significance of Pneumocephalus in Pediatric Mild Traumatic Brain Injury.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PEC.0000000000003060</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI) comprises most (70%-90%) of all pediatric head trauma cases seeking emergency care. Although most mTBI cases have normal initial head computed tomography scan, a considerable portion of the cases have intracranial imaging abnormalities on computed tomography scan. Whereas other intracranial pathological findings have been extensively studied, little is known about the clinical significance of pneumocephalus in pediatric mTBI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively identified pediatric mTBI patients with pneumocephalus using the institutional database of a large regional trauma referral center. Outcome measures were defined as clinically important TBI (ciTBI), hospitalization, intensive care unit (ICU) admission, and neurosurgical intervention. Comparisons were made between pneumocephalus and control (isolated linear fracture) groups as well as between isolated (only linear fracture and pneumocephalus) and nonisolated pneumocephalus (pneumocephalus and TBI) groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 3524 pediatric mTBI cases, 43 cases had pneumocephalus (1.2%). Twenty-one cases (48.8%) had isolated pneumocephalus. The pneumocephalus group had higher rates of ciTBI, hospital admission, ICU admission, and neurosurgery when compared with the isolated linear fracture (control) group. The isolated pneumocephalus group had fewer ciTBI (21.1% vs 70%, P = 0.002), fewer hospitalization (23.8% vs 81.8%, P &lt; 0.001), but similar ICU admission rates (4.8% vs 22.7%, P = 0.089) and length of hospital stay (4.0 &#xb1; 2.7 vs 3.6 &#xb1; 2.4 days, P = 0.798) in comparison to the nonisolated pneumocephalus group. None of the patients in the isolated group had neurosurgery whereas 2 patients in the nonisolated pneumocephalus group underwent surgery. Multivariable analysis revealed pneumocephalus as an independent predictor of ciTBI and hospital admission, but not ICU admission or neurosurgical intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Pneumocephalus is associated with increased rates of hospitalization and ciTBI, but not ICU admission, unfavorable outcome, or neurosurgical intervention in pediatric mTBI. Although usually spontaneously resolving pathology, it may occasionally be linked with complications such as cerebrospinal fluid leakage, meningitis, and tension pneumocephalus. Therefore, careful evaluation, close observation, and early detection of complications may prevent adverse outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanalioglu</LastName><ForeName>Damla</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elbir</LastName><ForeName>Cagri</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Health Sciences, Diskapi Yildirim Beyazit Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahin</LastName><ForeName>Omer Selcuk</ForeName><Initials>OS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Health Sciences, Diskapi Yildirim Beyazit Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ercandirli</LastName><ForeName>Aziz Kaan</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Health Sciences, Diskapi Yildirim Beyazit Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahin</LastName><ForeName>Balkan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Health Sciences, Sisli Hamidiye Etfal Training and Research Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turkoglu</LastName><ForeName>Mehmet Erhan</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Health Sciences, Diskapi Yildirim Beyazit Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kertmen</LastName><ForeName>Huseyin Hayri</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, University of Health Sciences, Diskapi Yildirim Beyazit Training and Research Hospital, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanalioglu</LastName><ForeName>Sahin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pediatr Emerg Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8507560</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0749-5161</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Disclosure: The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37815282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PEC.0000000000003060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006565-990000000-00342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dewan MC, Mummareddy N, Wellons JC 3rd, et al. Epidemiology of global pediatric traumatic brain injury: qualitative review. World Neurosurg. 2016;91:497&#x2013;509.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haydel MJ, Preston CA, Mills TJ, et al. Indications for computed tomography in patients with minor head injury. N Engl J Med. 2000;343:100&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuppermann N, Holmes JF, Dayan PS, et al. Identification of children at very low risk of clinically-important brain injuries after head trauma: a prospective cohort study. Lancet. 2009;374:1160&#x2013;1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes JF, Borgialli DA, Nadel FM, et al. Do children with blunt head trauma and normal cranial computed tomography scan results require hospitalization for neurologic observation? Ann Emerg Med. 2011;58:315&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marincowitz C, Lecky FE, Townend W, et al. The risk of deterioration in GCS13&#x2013;15 patients with traumatic brain injury identified by computed tomography imaging: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurotrauma. 2018;35:703&#x2013;718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lumba-Brown A, Yeates KO, Sarmiento K, et al. Diagnosis and management of mild traumatic brain injury in children: a systematic review. JAMA Pediatr. 2018;172:e182847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar-Shea AL, Ma&#xf1;as-Gallardo N, Romero-Pisonero E. Post-traumatic pneumocephalus. Int J Emerg Med. 2009;2:129&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eftekhar B, Ghodsi M, Nejat F, et al. Prophylactic administration of ceftriaxone for the prevention of meningitis after traumatic pneumocephalus: results of a clinical trial. J Neurosurg. 2004;101:757&#x2013;761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskil S, Baykaner K, &#xc7;eviker N, et al. Clinical significance of acute traumatic intracranial pneumocephalus. Neurosurg Rev. 1998;21:10&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Sharma A, Sengar R, et al. Post traumatic pneumocephalus: a tertiary institute experience. GJRA. 2018;7:401&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eom KS. Clinical and radiological characteristics of traumatic pneumocephalus after traumatic brain injury. Korean J Neurotrauma. 2020;16:49&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steudel WI, Hacker H. Prognosis, incidence and management of acute traumatic intracranial pneumocephalus. A retrospective analysis of 49 cases. Acta Neurochir (Wien). 1986;80:93&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard A, Cabrera KI, Kuppermann N, et al. Acute outcomes of isolated pneumocephali in children after minor blunt head trauma. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2018;34:656&#x2013;660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markham JW. The clinical features of pneumocephalus based upon a survey of 284 cases with report of 11 additional cases. Acta Neurochir. 1967;16:1&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oge K, Akpinar G, Bertan V. Traumatic subdural pneumocephalus causing rise in intracranial pressure in the early phase of head trauma: report of two cases. Acta Neurochir. 1998;140:655&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomiichuk V, Lebed V, Drizhdov K. Posttraumatic delayed subdural tension pneumocephalus. Surg Neurol Int. 2013;4:37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborn AG, Daines JH, Wing SD, et al. Intracranial air on computerized tomography. J Neurosurg. 1978;48:355&#x2013;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yucetas SC, Yildirim CH, Kaya M, et al. Pneumocephalus after traumatic head injury: our experience with 73 cases in a tertiary care center. Neurosurgery Quarterly. 2015;25:250&#x2013;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns EC, Grool AM, Klassen TP, et al. Scalp hematoma characteristics associated with intracranial injury in pediatric minor head injury. Acad Emerg Med. 2016;23:576&#x2013;583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reider-Grosswasser I, Godel V, Lazar M. Computed tomography in ethmoid cell trauma. Comput Radiol. 1982;6:171&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons J, Luks AM. Tension pneumocephalus: an uncommon cause of altered mental status. J Emerg Med. 2013;44:340&#x2013;343.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>