<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37810284</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2229-5097</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Surgical neurology international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Surg Neurol Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Primary central nervous system lymphoma in elderly: An illustrative case of the new role of surgery and integrative medical management.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>310</StartPage><MedlinePgn>310</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">310</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/SNI_431_2023</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Primary central nervous system lymphoma (PCNSL) is a rare, aggressive non-Hodgkin lymphoproliferative neoplasm. Surgery is traditionally limited to biopsy due to past studies, but recent strong evidence continues to challenge this status quo in selected patients. Here, the authors characterize a case to illustrate the potential role of surgery and foster research on integrative medical management approaches for this disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE DESCRIPTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A 73-year-old woman was admitted to the hospital with aphasia and confusion. Neuroimaging suggested a lymphoproliferative process. The patient underwent cytoreductive surgery to resect the lesion. Microscopically, large infiltrating lymphoid cells that induced brain tissue damage were observed, and a diagnosis of diffuse large B-cell lymphoma was made based on immunohistochemistry. The patient evolved clinically post surgery. A complete response to further chemotherapy maintained the patient's clinical recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This rare case highlights the potential of surgical intervention in the management of selected patients with PCNSL. The authors also underscore the recent, meta-analytic evidence on surgery followed by combined chemotherapy for the management of specific cases. The reported recovery in an elderly patient is noteworthy and adds to the literature on this rare subtype of brain tumors. Future research should consider investigating a potential profile of candidates for resection and combined chemotherapy in PCNSL.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 Surgical Neurology International.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fiedler</LastName><ForeName>Augusto M&#xfc;ller</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, University of Miami Hospital, Miami, Florida, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Filho</LastName><ForeName>Paulo Moacir Mesquita</ForeName><Initials>PMM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Affiliated Hospital of Atitus Education School of Medicine, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morassutti</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra Loureiro</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, School of Medicine and Postgraduate Program in Dentistry, University of Passo Fundo, Passo Fundo, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rottenfusser</LastName><ForeName>Robson</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Affiliated Hospital of Atitus Education School of Medicine, Passo Fundo, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varela</LastName><ForeName>Daniel Lima</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Affiliated Hospital of Atitus Education School of Medicine, Passo Fundo, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Surg Neurol Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101535836</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2152-7806</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain tumor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma (DLBCL)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuro-oncology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary central nervous system lymphoma (PCNSL)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37810284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10559532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25259/SNI_431_2023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.25259/SNI_431_2023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bravetti C, Degaud M, Armand M, Sourdeau E, Mokhtari K, Maloum K, et al. Combining MYD88 L265P mutation detection and clonality determination on CSF cellular and cell-free DNA improves diagnosis of primary CNS lymphoma. Br J Haematol. 2023;201:1088&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36941788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chojak R, Ko&#x17a;ba-Goszty&#x142;a M, Pola&#x144;ska K, Rojek M, Chojko A, Bogacz R, et al. Surgical resection versus biopsy in the treatment of primary central nervous system lymphoma: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurooncol. 2022;160:753&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9758097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36449256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franca RA, Travaglino A, Varricchio S, Russo D, Picardi M, Pane F, et al. HIV prevalence in primary central nervous system lymphoma: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Pathol Res Pract. 2020;216:153192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32956921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guha A, Goda JS, Dasgupta A, Mahajan A, Halder S, Gawde J, et al. Classifying primary central nervous system lymphoma from glioblastoma using deep learning and radiomics based machine learning approach-a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Oncol. 2022;12:884173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9574102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36263203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang-Xuan K, Bessell E, Bromberg J, Hottinger AF, Preusser M, Rud&#xe0; R, et al. Diagnosis and treatment of primary CNS lymphoma in immunocompetent patients: Guidelines from the European Association for Neuro-Oncology. Lancet Oncol. 2015;16:e322&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26149884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoang-Xuan K, Deckert M, Ferreri AJ, Furtner J, Perez-Larraya J, Henriksson R, et al. European Association of Neuro-Oncology (EANO) guidelines for treatment of primary central nervous system lymphoma (PCNSL) Neuro Oncol. 2023;25:37&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9825335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35953526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horbinski C, Nabors LB, Portnow J, Baehring J, Bhatia A, Bloch O, et al. NCCN guidelines&#xae; insights: Central nervous system cancers, version 2.2022. J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2023;21:12&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36634606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houillier C, Soussain C, Ghesqui&#xe8;res H, Soubeyran P, Chinot O, Taillandier L, et al. Management and outcome of primary CNS lymphoma in the modern era: An LOC network study. Neurology. 2020;94:e1027&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7238921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huntoon K, Makary MS, Shah VS, Aquino A, Pandya V, Giglio P, et al. Pretreatment findings on magnetic resonance imaging in primary central nervous system lymphoma may predict overall survival duration. Neuroradiol J. 2023;36:479&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36715098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerbauy MN, Moraes FY, Lok BH, Ma J, Kerbauy LN, Spratt DE, et al. Challenges and opportunities in primary CNS lymphoma: A systematic review. Radiother Oncol. 2017;122:352&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28104300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna S, Kakaizada S, Almeida N, Brang D, Hervey-Jumper S. Central nervous system plasticity influences language and cognitive recovery in adult glioma. Neurosurgery. 2021;89:539&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33476391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurz KS, Ott G. The 5th edition of the WHO classification of lymphoid neoplasms-an overview. Pathologie (Heidelb) 2022;43:64&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36239779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Huang Y, Bi C, Yuan J, He H, Zhang H, et al. Primary central nervous system diffuse large B-cell lymphoma shows an activated B-cell-like phenotype with co-expression of C-MYC, BCL-2, and BCL-6. Pathol Res Pract. 2017;213:659&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28552541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis DN, Perry A, Wesseling P, Brat DJ, Cree IA, FigarellaBranger D, et al. The 2021 WHO classification of tumors of the central nervous system: A summary. Neuro Oncol. 2021;23:1231&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8328013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34185076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales H. Current and future challenges of functional MRI and diffusion tractography in the surgical setting: From eloquent brain mapping to neural plasticity. Semin Ultrasound CT MR. 2021;42:474&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34537116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morell AA, Shah AH, Cavallo C, Eichberg DG, Sarkiss CA, Benveniste R, et al. Diagnosis of primary central nervous system lymphoma: A systematic review of the utility of CSF screening and the role of early brain biopsy. Neurooncol Pract. 2019;6:415&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6899047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31832211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo SS, Cleveland J, Rubenstein JL. Primary CNS lymphoma: Update on molecular pathogenesis and therapy. Leuk Lymphoma. 2023;64:57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36286546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrom QT, Price M, Neff C, Cioffi G, Waite KA, Kruchko C, et al. CBTRUS statistical report: Primary brain and other central nervous system tumors diagnosed in the United States in 2015-2019. Neuro Oncol. 2022;24:v1&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9533228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36196752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaguchi J, Ohka F, Kitano Y, Maeda S, Motomura K, Aoki K, et al. Rapid detection of the MYD88 L265P mutation for preand intra-operative diagnosis of primary central nervous system lymphoma. Cancer Sci. 2023;114:2544&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10236607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36859777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J, Du H, Ye X, Zhang L, Xiao H. High-dose methotrexate-based regimens and post-remission consolidation for treatment of newly diagnosed primary CNS lymphoma: Meta-analysis of clinical trials. Sci Rep. 2021;11:2125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7822904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33483528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>