<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2023//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_230101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37814134</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-0584</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of hematology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Hematol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>IL-10 plus the EASIX score predict bleeding events after anti-CD19 CAR T-cell therapy.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00277-023-05477-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chimeric antigen receptor (CAR) T-cell-associated coagulopathy can cause bleeding events. To explore risk factors for hemorrhage after CAR T-cell therapy, we retrospectively analyzed routine indicators in 56 patients with non-Hodgkin lymphoma and B-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia who received anti-CD19 CAR T-cell therapy. Disturbance of coagulation occurred mainly within one month post infusion, especially on day 7 and 14. The cumulative incidence of bleeding events within one month was 32.8%, with the median onset of 7 (range, 0-28) days. All bleeding events were grade 1-3. Patients who experienced bleeding events within one month had longer prothrombin time, higher IL-6, higher IL-10, and lower platelets before lymphodepletion. There were also correlations among coagulation-, inflammatory-, and tumor burden-related markers. Multi-variate analysis showed IL-10 (&gt; 7.98 pg/mL; adjusted odds ratio [OR], 13.84; 95% confidence interval [CI], 2.03-94.36; P = 0.007) and the endothelial activation and stress index (EASIX, defined as dehydrogenase [U/L] &#xd7; creatinine [mg/dL] / platelets [&#xd7;10<sup>9</sup> cells/L]; &gt;7.65; adjusted OR, 7.06; 95% CI, 1.03-48.23; P = 0.046) were significant risk factors for bleeding events. IL-10 plus the EASIX defined three risk groups for bleeding events with cumulative incidence of 100% (hazard ratio [HR], 14.47; 95% CI, 2.78-75.29; P &lt; 0.0001), 38.5% (HR, 3.68; 95% CI, 0.82-16.67; P = 0.089), and 11.8% (reference), respectively. Future studies are needed to verify the risk assessment models for bleeding events after CAR T-cell treatment in larger cohorts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xindi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hematology, Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Clinical Medical Center of Cell Therapy for Neoplastic Disease, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Chenggong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hematology, Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Clinical Medical Center of Cell Therapy for Neoplastic Disease, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Wenjing</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hematology, Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Clinical Medical Center of Cell Therapy for Neoplastic Disease, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yinqiang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hematology, Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Clinical Medical Center of Cell Therapy for Neoplastic Disease, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Zhongpei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hematology, Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Clinical Medical Center of Cell Therapy for Neoplastic Disease, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hematology, Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Clinical Medical Center of Cell Therapy for Neoplastic Disease, Wuhan, 430022, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mei</LastName><ForeName>Heng</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7941-2443</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hematology, Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430022, China. hmei@hust.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Clinical Medical Center of Cell Therapy for Neoplastic Disease, Wuhan, 430022, China. hmei@hust.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Hematology, Union Hospital, Tongji Medical College, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430022, China. dr_huyu@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Clinical Medical Center of Cell Therapy for Neoplastic Disease, Wuhan, 430022, China. dr_huyu@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Hematol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9107334</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0939-5555</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bleeding events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelial activation and stress index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-10</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37814134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00277-023-05477-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00277-023-05477-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Locke FL, Ghobadi A, Jacobson CA, Miklos DB, Lekakis LJ, Oluwole OO, Lin Y, Braunschweig I, Hill BT, Timmerman JM, Deol A, Reagan PM, Stiff P, Flinn IW, Farooq U, Goy A, McSsweeney PA, Munoz J, Siddiqi T et al (2019) Long-term safety and activity of axicabtagene ciloleucel in refractory large B-cell lymphoma (ZUMA-1): a single-arm, multicentre, phase 1&#x2013;2 trial. Lancet Oncol 20(1):31&#x2013;42</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30518502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(18)30864-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Rivi&#xe8;re I, Gonen M, Wang X, S&#xe9;n&#xe9;chal B, Curran KJ, Sauter C, Wang Y, Santomasso B, Mead E, Roshal M, Maslak P, Davila M, Brentjens RJ, Sadelain M (2018) Long-term follow-up of CD19 CAR therapy in acute lymphoblastic leukemia. N Engl J Med 378(5):449&#x2013;459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29385376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6637939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1709919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maude SL, Laetsch TW, Buechner J, Rives S, Boyer M, Bittencourt H, Bader P, Verneris MR, Stefanski HE, Myers GD, Qayed M, De Moerloose B, Hiramatsu H, Schlis K, Davis KL, Martin PL, Nemecek ER, Yanik GA, Peters C et al (2018) Tisagenlecleucel in children and young adults with B-cell lymphoblastic leukemia. New Engl J Med 378(5):439&#x2013;448</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29385370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1709866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei H, Chen F, Han Y, Hou M, Huang H, Huang X, Li Y, Liang A, Liu Q, Niu T, Peng J, Qian W, Song Y, Wang J, Wang Y, Wu D, Xu K, Yang L, Yang R et al (2022) Chinese expert consensus on the management of chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy-associated coagulopathy. Chin Med J 135(14):1639&#x2013;1641</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35984103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9509066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CM9.0000000000002288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamasaki-Morita M, Arai Y, Ishihara T, Onishi T, Shimo H, Nakanishi K, Nishiyama Y, Jo T, Hiramatsu H, Mitsuyoshi T, Mizumoto C, Kanda J, Nishikori M, Kitawaki T, Nogami K, Takaori-Kondo A, Nagao M, Adachi S (2022) Relative hypercoagulation induced by suppressed fibrinolysis after tisagenlecleucel infusion in malignant lymphoma. Blood Adv 6(14):4216&#x2013;4223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35580321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9327547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2022007454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara T, Arai Y, Morita M, Onishi T, Shimo H, Kitawaki T, Takaori-Kondo A, Adachi S, Nogami K (2021) Suppressed fibrinolytic activity demonstrated by simultaneous thrombin and plasmin generation assay during cytokine release syndrome after CD19 chimeric antigen receptor-modified T-cell therapy. Blood 138(Supplement 1):4807&#x2013;4807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2021-146311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belbachir S, Tudesq JJ, Lamure S, Rocanieres P, Properzi E, Ceballos P, Fegueux N, Gehlkopf E, Paul F, Tchernonog E, Theron A, Teyssier A-C, Diaz I, Patricia A-M, Herbaux C, Cartron G (2021) Coagulopathy following chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy in R/R adult B cell malignancies: a single center experience. Blood 138(Supplement 1):4839&#x2013;4839</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2021-152465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Qi K, Cheng H, Cao J, Shi M, Qiao J, Yan Z, Jing G, Pan B, Sang W, Li D, Wang X, Fu C, Zhu F, Zheng J, Li Z, Xu K (2020) Coagulation disorders after chimeric antigen receptor T cell therapy: analysis of 100 patients with relapsed and refractory hematologic malignancies. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant 26(5):865&#x2013;875</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31786240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbmt.2019.11.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei H, Jiang H, Wu Y, Guo T, Xia L, Jin R, Hu Y (2018) Neurological toxicities and coagulation disorders in the cytokine release syndrome during CAR-T therapy. Br J Haematol 181(5):689&#x2013;692</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28369673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjh.14680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao M, Yu Q, Teng X, Guo X, Wei G, Xu H, Cui J, Chang AH, Hu Y, Huang H (2021) CRS-related coagulopathy in BCMA targeted CAR-T therapy: a retrospective analysis in a phase I/II clinical trial. Bone Marrow Transplant 56(7):1642&#x2013;1650</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33608658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41409-021-01226-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Cao J, Cheng H, Qiao J, Zhang H, Wang Y, Shi M, Lan J, Fei X, Jin L, Jing G, Sang W, Zhu F, Chen W, Wu Q, Yao Y, Wang G, Zhao J, Zheng J et al (2019) A combination of humanised anti-CD19 and anti-BCMA CAR T cells in patients with relapsed or refractory multiple myeloma: a single-arm, phase 2 trial. Lancet Haematol 6(10):e521&#x2013;e529</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31378662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3026(19)30115-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan J, Tan Y, Wang G, Deng B, Ling Z, Song W, Seery S, Zhang Y, Peng S, Xu J, Duan J, Wang Z, Yu X, Zheng Q, Xu X, Yuan Y, Yan F, Tian Z, Tang K et al (2021) Donor-derived CD7 chimeric antigen receptor T cells for T-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia: first-in-human, phase I trial. J Clin Oncol 39(30):3340&#x2013;3351</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34324392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.21.00389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsrud A, Craig J, Baird J, Spiegel J, Muffly L, Zehnder J, Tamaresis J, Negrin R, Johnston L, Arai S, Shizuru J, Lowsky R, Meyer E, Weng WK, Shiraz P, Rezvani A, Latchford T, Mackall C, Miklos D et al (2021) Incidence and risk factors associated with bleeding and thrombosis following chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy. Blood Adv 5(21):4465&#x2013;4475</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34521106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8579267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2021004716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashmi H, Mirza AS, Darwin A, Logothetis C, Garcia F, Kommalapati A, Mhaskar RS, Bachmeier C, Chavez JC, Shah B, Pinilla-Ibarz J, Khimani F, Lazaryan A, Liu H, Davila ML, Locke FL, Nishihori T, Jain MD (2020) Venous thromboembolism associated with CD19-directed CAR T-cell therapy in large B-cell lymphoma. Blood Adv 4(17):4086&#x2013;4090</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7479945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020002060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H, Liu L, Guo T, Wu Y, Ai L, Deng J, Dong J, Mei H, Hu Y (2019) Improving the safety of CAR-T cell therapy by controlling CRS-related coagulopathy. Ann Hematol 98(7):1721&#x2013;1732</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31055613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00277-019-03685-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi J, Lv X, Chen J, Wang H, Chu T, Tang Y, Pan T, Zhou M, Cai C, Ren Y, Liu Y, Fan Y, Shen W, Ma X, Qiu H, Tang X, Fu C, Wu D, Han Y (2022) TNF-alpha increases the risk of bleeding in patients after CAR T-cell therapy: a bleeding model based on a real-world study of Chinese CAR T Working Party. Hematol Oncol 40(1):63&#x2013;71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34606093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hon.2931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locke FL, Rossi JM, Neelapu SS, Jacobson CA, Miklos DB, Ghobadi A, Oluwole OO, Reagan PM, Lekakis LJ, Lin Y, Sherman M, Better M, Go WY, Wiezorek JS, Xue A, Bot A (2020) Tumor burden, inflammation, and product attributes determine outcomes of axicabtagene ciloleucel in large B-cell lymphoma. Blood Adv 4(19):4898&#x2013;4911</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33035333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7556133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020002394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Samkari H, Karp Leaf RS, Dzik WH, Carlson JCT, Fogerty AE, Waheed A, Goodarzi K, Bendapudi PK, Bornikova L, Gupta S, Leaf DE, Kuter DJ, Rosovsky RP (2020) COVID-19 and coagulation: bleeding and thrombotic manifestations of SARS-CoV-2 infection. Blood 136(4):489&#x2013;500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2020006520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Chen W, Lin M, Chen G, Chen C, Huo C, Du X (2021) Correlation of 18F-FDG PET/CT SUVmax with clinical features D-dimer and LDH in patients with primary intestinal lymphoma. J Int Med Res 49(7):3000605211029809</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34250823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03000605211029809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hinsbergh VW (2012) Endothelium&#x2014;role in regulation of coagulation and inflammation. Semin Immunopathol 34(1):93&#x2013;106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21845431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00281-011-0285-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruutu T, Barosi G, Benjamin RJ, Clark RE, George JN, Gratwohl A, Holler E, Iacobelli M, Kentouche K, L&#xe4;mmle B, Moake JL, Richardson P, Soci&#xe9; G, Zeigler Z, Niederwieser D, Barbui T (2007) Diagnostic criteria for hematopoietic stem cell transplant-associated microangiopathy: results of a consensus process by an International Working Group. Haematologica 92(1):95&#x2013;100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17229640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3324/haematol.10699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luft T, Benner A, Jodele S, Dandoy CE, Storb R, Gooley T, Sandmaier BM, Becker N, Radujkovic A, Dreger P, Penack O (2017) EASIX in patients with acute graft-versus-host disease: a retrospective cohort analysis. Lancet Haematol 4(9):e414&#x2013;e423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28733186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2352-3026(17)30108-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennisi M, Sanchez-Escamilla M, Flynn JR, Shouval R, Alarcon Tomas A, Silverberg ML, Batlevi C, Brentjens RJ, Dahi PB, Devlin SM, Diamonte C, Giralt S, Halton EF, Jain T, Maloy M, Mead E, Palomba ML, Ruiz J, Santomasso B et al (2021) Modified EASIX predicts severe cytokine release syndrome and neurotoxicity after chimeric antigen receptor T cells. Blood Adv 5(17):3397&#x2013;3406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34432870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8525234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020003885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korell F, Penack O, Mattie M, Schreck N, Benner A, Krzykalla J, Wang Z, Schmitt M, Bullinger L, Muller-Tidow C, Dreger P, Luft T (2022) EASIX and severe endothelial complications after CD19-directed CAR-T cell therapy&#x2014;a cohort study. Front Immunol 13:877477</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35464403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9033201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.877477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenbaum U, Strati P, Saliba RM, Torres J, Rondon G, Nieto Y, Hosing C, Srour SA, Westin J, Fayad LE, Lee HJ, Iyer SP, Nair R, Nastoupil LJ, Parmar S, Rodriguez MA, Samaniego F, Steiner RE, Wang M et al (2021) CRP and ferritin in addition to the EASIX score predict CAR-T-related toxicity. Blood Adv 5(14):2799&#x2013;2806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34264268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8341350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2021004575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhou F, Wu Z, Li Y, Li C, Du M, Luo W, Kou H, Lu C, Mei H (2022) Timing of tocilizumab administration under the guidance of IL-6 in CAR-T therapy for R/R acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Front Immunol 13:914959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35799791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9253384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.914959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo W, Li C, Wu J, Tang L, Wang X, Zhang Y, Wu Z, Huang Z, Xu J, Kang Y, Xiong W, Deng J, Hu Y, Mei H (2023) Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitors preserve anti-CD19 chimeric antigen receptor T-cell functionality and reprogram tumor micro-environment in B-cell lymphoma. Cytotherapy 25(7):739&#x2013;749</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37074239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcyt.2023.03.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AB, Hoogstraten B, Staquet M, Winkler A (1981) Reporting results of cancer treatment. Cancer 47(1):207&#x2013;214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7459811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1097-0142(19810101)47:1&lt;207::AID-CNCR2820470134&gt;3.0.CO;2-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DW, Santomasso BD, Locke FL, Ghobadi A, Turtle CJ, Brudno JN, Maus MV, Park JH, Mead E, Pavletic S, Go WY, Eldjerou L, Gardner RA, Frey N, Curran KJ, Peggs K, Pasquini M, DiPersio JF, van den Brink MRM et al (2019) ASTCT consensus grading for cytokine release syndrome and neurologic toxicity associated with immune effector cells. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant 25(4):625&#x2013;638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30592986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbmt.2018.12.758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buechner J, Grupp SA, Hiramatsu H, Teachey DT, Rives S, Laetsch TW, Yanik GA, Wood P, Awasthi R, Yi L, Chassot-Agostinho A, Eldjerou LK, De Moerloose B (2021) Practical guidelines for monitoring and management of coagulopathy following tisagenlecleucel CAR T-cell therapy. Blood Adv 5(2):593&#x2013;601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33496754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7839371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020002757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santomasso BD, Nastoupil LJ, Adkins S, Lacchetti C, Schneider BJ, Anadkat M, Atkins MB, Brassil KJ, Caterino JM, Chau I, Davies MJ, Ernstoff MS, Fecher L, Funchain P, Jaiyesimi I, Mammen JS, Naidoo J, Naing A, Phillips T et al (2021) Management of immune-related adverse events in patients treated with chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy: ASCO guideline. J Clin Oncol 39(35):3978&#x2013;3992</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34724386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.21.01992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juluri KR, Wu QV, Voutsinas J, Hou J, Hirayama AV, Mullane E, Miles N, Maloney DG, Turtle CJ, Bar M, Gauthier J (2022) Severe cytokine release syndrome is associated with hematologic toxicity following CD19 CAR T-cell therapy. Blood Adv 6(7):2055&#x2013;2068</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34666344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9006285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020004142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otani T, Sawano H, Natsukawa T, Matsuoka R, Nakashima T, Takahagi M, Hayashi Y (2018) D-dimer predicts bleeding complication in out-of-hospital cardiac arrest resuscitated with ECMO. Am J Emerg Med 36(6):1003&#x2013;1008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29129499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2017.11.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissani A, Lev-Ari S, Meirson T, Jacoby E, Asher N, Ben-Betzalel G, Itzhaki O, Shapira-Frommer R, Schachter J, Markel G, Besser MJ (2021) Comparison of non-myeloablative lymphodepleting preconditioning regimens in patients undergoing adoptive T cell therapy. J Immunother Cancer&#xa0;9(5):e001743</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreyro BL, Scales DC, Wunsch H, Cheung MC, Gupta V, Saskin R, Thyagu S, Munshi L (2021) Critical illness in patients with hematologic malignancy: a population-based cohort study. Intensive Care Med 47(10):1104&#x2013;1114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34519845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-021-06502-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachman RL, Rafii S (2008) Platelets, petechiae, and preservation of the vascular wall. N Engl J Med 359(12):1261&#x2013;1270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2935201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra0800887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Liu XL, Zhang D, Liu F, Cheng YJ, Ma Y, Zhou YJ, Zhao YX (2019) Platelet-derived exosomes affect the proliferation and migration of human umbilical vein endothelial cells via miR-126. Curr Vasc Pharmacol 17(4):379&#x2013;387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29532758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570161116666180313142139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadamuro M, Brivio S, Mertens J, Vismara M, Moncsek A, Milani C, Fingas C, Cristina Malerba M, Nardo G, Dall&#x2019;Olmo L, Milani E, Mariotti V, Stecca T, Massani M, Spirli C, Fiorotto R, Indraccolo S, Strazzabosco M, Fabris L (2019) Platelet-derived growth factor-D enables liver myofibroblasts to promote tumor lymphangiogenesis in cholangiocarcinoma. J Hepatol 70(4):700&#x2013;709</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30553841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2018.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Cedervall J, Hamidi A, Herre M, Viitaniemi K, D&#x2019;Amico G, Miao Z, Unnithan RVM, Vaccaro A, van Hooren L, Georganaki M, Thulin &#xc5;, Qiao Q, Andrae J, Siegbahn A, Heldin CH, Alitalo K, Betsholtz C, Dimberg A, Olsson AK (2020) Platelet-specific PDGFB ablation impairs tumor vessel integrity and promotes metastasis. Cancer Res 80(16):3345&#x2013;3358</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32586981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-19-3533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langstrom S, Koskenvuo M, Huttunen P, Lassila R, Taskinen M, Ranta S, Heikinheimo M, Makipernaa A (2018) Haematopoietic stem cell transplantation in children shifts the coagulation system towards a pro-coagulant state. Thromb Haemost 118(8):1390&#x2013;1396</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29960273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0038-1661394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hokama LT, Veiga ADM, Menezes MCS, Sardinha Pinto AA, de Lima TM, Ariga SKK, Barbeiro HV, Barbeiro DF, de Lucena Moreira C, Stanzani G, Brandao RA, Marchini JF, Alencar JC, Marino LO, Gomez LM, U.S.P.C.-G. Emergency, H.P. Souza (2022) Endothelial injury in COVID-19 and septic patients. Microvasc Res 140:104303</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34914941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mvr.2021.104303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strati P, Nastoupil LJ, Westin J, Fayad LE, Ahmed S, Fowler NH, Hagemeister FB, Lee HJ, Iyer SP, Nair R, Parmar S, Rodriguez MA, Samaniego F, Steiner RE, Wang M, Pinnix CC, Adkins S, Claussen CM, Martinez CS et al (2020) Clinical and radiologic correlates of neurotoxicity after axicabtagene ciloleucel in large B-cell lymphoma. Blood Adv 4(16):3943&#x2013;3951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32822484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7448589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2020002228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner DD, Frenette PS (2008) The vessel wall and its interactions. Blood 111(11):5271&#x2013;5281</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18502843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2396724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2008-01-078204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Probst K, Fijnheer R, Rothova A (2004) Endothelial cell activation and hypercoagulability in ocular Behcet's disease. Am J Ophthalmol 137(5):850&#x2013;857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15126149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajo.2003.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z, Lin B, Jia X, Su T, Wei Y, Tang J, Yang C, Cui C, Liu J (2021) Enhanced IL-10 inhibits proliferation and promotes apoptosis of HUVECs through STAT3 signaling pathway in sepsis. Histol Histopathol 36(11):1179&#x2013;1187</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34528700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short WD, Steen E, Kaul A, Wang X, Olutoye OO 2nd, Vangapandu HV, Templeman N, Blum AJ, Moles CM, Narmoneva DA, Crombleholme TM, Butte MJ, Bollyky PL, Keswani SG, Balaji S (2022) IL-10 promotes endothelial progenitor cell infiltration and wound healing via STAT3. FASEB J 36(7):e22298</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35670763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.201901024RR</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S, Tanaka T, Inoue H, Ono C, Hashimoto S, Kioi Y, Matsumoto H, Matsuura H, Matsubara T, Shimizu K, Ogura H, Matsuura Y, Kishimoto T (2020) IL-6 trans-signaling induces plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 from vascular endothelial cells in cytokine release syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 117(36):22351&#x2013;22356</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7486751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2010229117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>